<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Creative Leicestershire]]></title><description><![CDATA[Advice, support + growth for creative enterprises across Leicester, Leicestershire + Rutland.]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 14:26:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[One Journeys Festival International - Three Cities - Ten Days]]></title><description><![CDATA[Journeys Festival International 15 - 24 October 2021 Leicester - Manchester - Portsmouth Journeys Festival International, the UK’s first...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/one-journeys-festival-international-three-cities-ten-days</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61485389ea762e00162be3f0</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 09:30:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1592927ec7a741cc96eeb9c397dacbb5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Journeys Festival International</strong></p>
<p><strong>15 - 24 October 2021</strong></p>
<p><strong>Leicester - Manchester - Portsmouth</strong></p>

<p>Journeys Festival International, the UK’s first festival of Sanctuary, has delivered the annual festival created by artists exploring the refugee experience and global cultures for almost a decade. In 2020, the pandemic decreed that the festival - which usually delivers at different points of the year in Leicester, Manchester and Portsmouth - went fully digital for the first time. However, in 2021 the team behind the festival have decided to go one step further and deliver the whole festival in three different cities during the same ten days this October.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1592927ec7a741cc96eeb9c397dacbb5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>'Where There is Light' will appear in each city during the festival. (Image credit: Mikal Ludlow)</strong></p>

<p>From 15 to 24 October, the three cities will be filled with large-scale exhibitions, performances, workshops, virtual reality experiences, global cuisine and digital projects, mostly for free or a small donation.  </p>

<p>Lorna Fulton, Creative Director for ArtReach, producers of the festival, shares the inspirations behind this new concept for the festival: “Even though programming festival activities in all three cities at the same time brings new challenges, we want to engage a broader audience by making the same artworks accessible in all three festival cities. This will give both the artists and audience members the possibility of exploring the artworks in more depth and increasing their impact by showcasing them in the Midlands, the North and the South of the country. Thanks to Arts Council England and Creative Europe funding we’re able to keep the majority of the festival free to attend too, helping us to reach new audiences across the nation.”</p>

<p>The programme includes a fantastic selection of cultural events and creative activities that will intrigue and entertain audience members up and down the country. Journeys Festival International wants to encourage people to stop by and engage with topics of refugee experiences and artists with sanctuary seeking backgrounds in a creative context. </p>

<p>Working with partners around the UK, the immersive sound and light installation Where There Is Light by Squidsoup captures the voices and stories of sanctuary seeking communities in Leicester, Portsmouth, Coventry and Hull, asking questions of connection and transformation in these current challenging times. Reckoning - by Choreographer and Storyteller Akeim Toussaint Buck as part of a collaboration with European artists - uses contemporary dance, animation and spoken word to weave the stories of generations of displaced people into a performance piece. The large-scale outdoor animation Bloodland Embrace by Majid Adin will bring local communities together to enjoy an evening of projections around favourite city centre locations.</p>

<p>With an amazing line-up of international artists, the festival will bring flavours of different cultures from around the world to Leicester, Manchester and Portsmouth – all at the same time! For more information, visit the website <a href="https://www.journeysfestival.com" target="_blank" >,<u>https://www.journeysfestival.com</u></a> </p>

<p><strong>Follow Journeys Festival here:</strong></p>
<p>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/JourneysFest"  >,<u>@JourneysFest</u></a></p>
<p>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/JourneysFest"  >,<u>@JourneysFest</u></a></p>
<p>Instagram: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/journeysfest/?hl=en"  >,<u>@journeysfest</u></a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ANTHRO ZOOLOGY: New Drawings by Tom Van Herrewege]]></title><description><![CDATA[A exhibition of new drawings by Tom Van Herrewege is inspired by a curiosity and awe of the evolutionary diversity of the animal kingdom,...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/anthro-zoology-new-drawings-by-tom-van-herrewege</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61177a993f7242001530043c</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 08:26:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_783cf20fe81740e3973624a7fdf35bfc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_725,h_421,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A exhibition of new drawings by Tom Van Herrewege is inspired by a curiosity and awe of the evolutionary diversity of the animal kingdom, and how mankind has interpreted this around the world throughout history and today.</strong></p><hr><p><u><strong>Anthrozoology / noun</strong></u></p>
<p>1. the interdisciplinary study of the interaction between humans and other animals.</p>

<p>Tom's work explores how animals have evolved into what they are and the incredible variety across this spectrum, alongside his interest in how animals exist in the human imagination, and the consequential impact that this has on the natural world.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_2927cc8fc13048a18f185be843796aa4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_990,h_983,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>It is how we understand them, categorize them, create ideas around them, worship and demonize them, utilize them, and the many other ways that humanity makes sense out of animals that is at the centre of his ideas.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_991c0e75399d4b6f80367eeaeb050a57~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>In these new charcoal drawings, he has created realist depictions of various species in wild landscapes that are decisively rendered to describe the physicality and the behaviour of these creatures. The use of charcoal and chalk to create atmosphere is gestural, with hand stencils and playful mark making that allude to prehistoric cave art and the first depictions of animals.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_2f5e33d24e554623afd504acb5561c5d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Overlayed across the initial images, he has added delicate chalk line drawings across the surface of each piece, which describe how we are familiar with these animals. These softer line drawings are provoking for the viewer to consider the ever-increasing extinction crisis and the effects of humanity, yet they also celebrate the powerful charisma of certain species and how this has been embraced in folklore, cartoons, art, and cinema.</p>

<p>The artists intentions are to make the viewer pause and reflect on why we look at animals in the way we do, and to celebrate the strange and fascinating ways that one animal (us), perceives another. It is to also make us consider the impact of this, and humanity’s place within the natural world.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1b3e846adbd2437e949238d44db00e4e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_984,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Anthro Zoology opens at </strong><a href="https://www.leicestercontemporary.co.uk/" target="_blank" ><strong><u>Leicester Contemporary</u></strong></a><strong> on 18th August and runs until 11th September.</strong> </p>

<p><strong>You can see more of Tom's work here -</strong></p>
<p><a href="www.tomvh.com" target="_blank" ><u><strong>www.tomvh.com</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="www.instagram.com/TomVanHerrewege/" target="_blank" ><u><strong>www.instagram.com/TomVanHerrewege/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Leicester Art Trail: Art on Tap]]></title><description><![CDATA[Leicester City Centre will be filled with colourful art trails as part of the Liberty UK Festival. Running from 10 July – 15 August, the...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/leicester-art-trail-art-on-tap</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60f55cf87118cd00154e43b4</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:09:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_97b4d432f57843a68bcd2e3e586241dc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leicester City Centre will be filled with colourful art trails as part of the <a href="www.libertyfestival.com" target="_blank" ><u>Liberty UK Festival</u></a>. Running from 10 July – 15 August, the festival is bringing together international artists and local artists to fill the town with brand new artworks in unusual locations.</p>

<p>Working with BID Leicester, Art on Tap, brings incredible new work to pub courtyards around the city centre. <a href="https://www.loyalfree.co.uk/" target="_blank" ><u>The Loyal Free App</u></a> will feature a trail of artwork that you can find in some of your favourite local pubs and bars. Art on Tap aims to bring the gallery to you so that you can enjoy new large-scale murals created by incredible artists over some choice refreshments as you take some time in the city centre. You’ll be able to enjoy Art on Tap by<a href="https://www.instagram.com/laura_pee_illustration/?hl=en" target="_blank" ><u> Laura Parker</u></a> at The Tree, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/katiefishlock/?hl=en" target="_blank" ><u>Katie Fishlock</u></a> at The Parcel Yard, <a href="https://www.zoepower.com/" target="_blank" ><u>Zoe Power</u></a> at the Rutland & Derby, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/the.rebel.bear/?hl=en" target="_blank" ><u>The Rebel Bear</u></a> at The Queen of Bradgate, and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/oliwia.bober/?hl=en" target="_blank" ><u>Oliwia Bober</u></a> at Cafe Bruxelles.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_97b4d432f57843a68bcd2e3e586241dc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>As part of a European-wide project called Accessible Art for All, the festival will also install some quirky installations in toilets of local shopping and cultural venues in the city centre.</p>

<p>Beth Piggott, Producer for the festival explained that, “We’re working with partners in Italy, Germany, Sweden and Bulgaria to place a series of high-impact installations into locations that we all use on a daily basis. Leicester is the first of these projects to take place but soon, all across Europe, people will experience artwork that questions important social issues in intimate locations. We’ve worked with some contemporary international artists to create this work and we’re excited to bring world-class contemporary visual art installations to a toilet near you soon!”</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_17b0c6c0c08842b8b60615f8f02dbd44~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Installations in toilets in Leicester include work by Polish illustrator Oliwia Bober, who draws influences in her work from Polish folklore, reflecting on her position as an immigrant in post-Brexit Britain which will be available to see in Highcross Shopping Centre; and Richard DeDomenici and his ‘Cubicle your Fears’ installation, revealing fears, hopes and dreams with strangers in the LCB Depot. Richard’s installation is inspired by his highly successful work, ‘Shed your Fears’ which appeared at Tate Gallery, YouTube Space and the British Museum.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_152ae75404344f528e604d2f06747d9e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Finally, created by Liberty Changemakers, a team of young people who have enjoyed a series of free artist-led workshops where they have learned how they can tackle problems they care about, Beauty in the Street is an outdoor exhibition installed onto the exteriors of buildings throughout the City Centre. Working with a team of highly specialised artists and campaigners the Liberty Changemakers have developed their own powerful social action campaigns and created poster art that shares messages of equality, diversity and compassion. </p>

<p>The Liberty UK Festival will return to Leicester in March 2022 after popping up in Halton in Liverpool in September and Corby in February next year.</p>

<p>Alongside the other exciting events that BID Leicester have planned for the summer it really does feel like there’s plenty of reasons to get back into and start enjoying summer in the city again.</p>

<p><strong>Find out more here - </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.libertyukfestival.com/"  ><strong><u>www.libertyfestival.com</u></strong></a></p>
<p><a href="www.artreach.biz" target="_blank" ><strong><u>www.artreach.biz</u></strong></a> </p>

<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/libertyfestivaluk/"  ><strong><u>@libertyfestivaluk</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Twitter: </strong><a href="https://twitter.com/_ArtReach"  ><strong><u>@_ArtReach</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/ArtReachEvents"  ><strong><u>@ArtReachEvents</u></strong></a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[NEW CONTEMPORARY ART GALLERY OPENS IN LEICESTER]]></title><description><![CDATA[A new temporary contemporary art gallery has opened on Market Street in Leicester. Andrew Birks, the artist behind the gallery tells us...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/new-contemporary-art-gallery-opens-in-leicester</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60d1bb2487e36c00158eead2</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:45:27 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_c8e33c5a136348abae2888e64a508f24~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A new temporary contemporary art gallery has opened on Market Street in Leicester. Andrew Birks, the artist behind the gallery tells us about the space and the artists involved.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_89ad7a7bd2684f459e253a1165072145~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p><strong>Where did the idea for a new studio/art gallery come about?</strong></p>

<p>Leicester doesn't have a dedicated art gallery in the city centre, yes there are galleries and exhibition spaces, but they are down a side street or on a university campus. I wanted to do something in the City Centre where everyone can see it, and freely walk in off the street to look around. The idea is not a new one really, pop up galleries have been done all over the place. I did one in Leicester when I was a student back in 1999, that was on Cank Street. It worked, and I thought it would be good to revisit the idea.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_c8e33c5a136348abae2888e64a508f24~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>So as I've said, the idea was mine and I'm leading the project, but I'm not alone. I have joined the Company of Artists. This is a new charitable interest company formed by Steven Allbutt, who is also the joint Director (with his wife Yuka Namekawa) of Studioname.  Steve has joined me by match funding the initial investment to get the project off the ground, but more important I think, is the belief, dedication and energy that has gone in so far! Other members of the Company of Artists are: Loz Atkinson, Tim Fowler, Matt Macken, Lucy Stevens and Tom Van Herrewege. All full time artists based in Studioname, Leicester.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_9e5acb817bd44bf099d7166f1120cbda~mv2.jpeg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a9fe54f565f84106968072bf06bf26ab~mv2.jpeg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_921d6340695c41ea973c823dbe8d1c93~mv2.jpeg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_48f9424ff00b4cb0b9d976fb3d7ce157~mv2.jpeg"></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about the location.</strong></p>

<p>The building is beautiful, Victorian, built in 1876 in the "Italianate Style". I was really surprised when I first saw it; an old betting shop hiding this secret hall with its elaborate dark wood beams, going up to around 15 metres in height. On the ground level It's been stripped out already with clean white walls, ready to show artwork, although there's a bit more work to do before we are ready to open.</p>

<p>The location is 16 Market Street; this is a street that has suffered over the last few years with one business after another closing or leaving. I suspect it's something to do with the expansion of the nearby Highcross Shopping Centre, but still, it's a great street, pedestrianised, with many other beautiful buildings- look up when you walk down there! </p>

<p>I hope that this project can help to kick off the rejuvenation of this street and bring something really positive to the City.  This is the City I grew up in, I'm quite proud of it and I want good things to happen, so I'm trying to make it happen rather than wait for someone else to do it.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4af951dc82954b44a703bdf6529dccd4~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_960,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p><strong>What can the public expect from the new gallery? </strong></p>

<p> What you can expect once we open is good contemporary art essentially. It kicks off with a group show of work by members of the Company of Artists. The rest of the program is still being developed, but it should include installation, solo shows, an open call exhibition and more. This will be supplemented by events that include spoken word, poetry and music. </p>
<p>Art work will be for sale; if you are in the market for a striking piece of contemporary art for your home or business, come down to the gallery, speak to the artists. There will be something that works for you either on show or back in the studio.</p>

<p>I think it's important to say that this gallery is temporary, it's only for a year initially. This has been made possible partly through the generosity of the building's owners. If it is successful, there will definitely be more, whether in the same location or another.</p>

<p><strong>Leicester Contemporary is now open until 9th July 2021. </strong></p>

<p><strong>Follow @leicestercontemporary on Instagram for news.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4a030f4057854abf80250284676ce0bc~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_678,h_960,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Up Your Street- bringing Art to the streets in a brand- new project funded by ArtsCouncil England]]></title><description><![CDATA[Three artists in Leicestershire break down barriers to accessing the arts as they bring their work out onto the streets where they live....]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/up-your-street-bringing-art-to-the-streets-in-a-brand-new-project-funded-by-artscouncil-england</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60c329e97bf9260015a16e12</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 09:03:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f7b864fe03fc48548b4c3300d443ddb2~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_707,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Three artists in Leicestershire break down barriers to accessing the arts as they bring their work out onto the streets where they live.</strong></p><hr><p>Thanks to funding from Arts Council England, Leicester-based Vehicle Arts are launching an</p>
<p>innovative new project-<a href="https://www.vehiclearts.uk/" target="_blank" ><u> <strong>Up Your Street</strong></u></a> that sees theatre and visual art being brought out </p>
<p>into the communities of Saffron Lane in Leicester, Leicester Forest East, and Loughborough. </p>

<p><strong>Up Your Street</strong> sees three local artists deliver work to their community across June and July. Each artist applied for the opportunity to be part of the project, which is managed by Vehicle Arts who work with emerging artists and give them opportunities to experiment and develop their craft.</p>

<p>Rebecca Harvey-Hobbs from Vehicle Arts said: “Since the pandemic, the Arts have been one of the most affected industries, with theatres and galleries all closed to the public. As we emerge from lockdown, it’s vital that we encourage audiences to engage with the Arts in different ways. Because we know that it may take a long while for some people to feel safe inside artistic spaces again. But the arts cannot be paused, so we need to find new ways of presenting them in the meantime, that’s why we are working with artists to take art out into the street and reach audiences beyond the gallery.”</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4a17414c365f406bb52322862a67db0e~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_cf3af5a8205443ddbb9397f866226ede~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_07800c781e2a4b29a53e108c11a9ade6~mv2.jpg"></figure><p>Louise Goodfield, Co-Company Director of Say It Again, Sorry? and who is the first artist to be presenting work in Up Your Street, said: “The opportunity to get creative on a local scale, literally in the street where we live, whilst developing our contacts and access to the community with Vehicle Arts support, was such an exciting prospect - we felt that this could help us to instil a sense of reassurance in the public that interactive theatre and participatory arts are needed more than ever, not just on a grand scale in big cities and state of the art theatres, but in high streets, parks and shopping centres - and it can be delivered just as safely in a post-covid era.”

She continued: “We’d like to thank Hobbycraft for supplying <strong>Easel Peasel </strong>with so many amazing art supplies to aid in connecting people to their inner artist! Hobbycraft will be opening a much- anticipated store in Thurmaston in Leicester in July and are already making such a positive impact on the community, as a result of this collaboration.”</p>

<p>Say It Again, Sorry?  will be presenting their project, <strong>Easel Peasel</strong> on Saturday 12th and Sunday 13th June on Park Drive, Leicester Forest East, 11am-4pm.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f7b864fe03fc48548b4c3300d443ddb2~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_707,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Easel Peasel</strong> is an interactive art experience that focuses on drawing the artist out of everybody. Participants can book for the characters to arrive at their front doors at a specified time via the Next Door App or can take part whenever they see the troupe running down the street. During the event, participants will receive a brand-new arts pack and Easel Peasel apron to help them engage with the activity as safely as possible. A standalone easel will be provided, including an array of colourful paints.</p>

<p>To Book: Message Say It Again, Sorry? on the Next Door App to have the characters arrive at your door, email hello@sayitagainsorry.co.uk or simply turn up and spot them in the street!</p>

<p>The second of the art installations is called <strong>Blooming Lovely </strong>and is created by Alison Carpenter-Hughes. It’s a bold and beautiful installation at the front of her house, incorporating a display of textiles and flowers using an array of upcycled items. The installation will be a celebration of life, renewal and joy; giving what Alison hopes will be a moment in time and place for people to stop, reflect and enjoy. Also, creating a little pit stop for pollinators!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_6527e7d06f844ddc836e11f97672ff6e~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_376,h_500,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Alison said: “I live on a typical city street; one that is busy, noisy and built up. There isn’t really any art in this area, so I wanted to bring an element of colour and creativity to the street, creating something that would be beneficial to nature and that has a use, that isn’t just nice to look at, and can be good for bees and other pollinators. My installation includes old, used and found objects, some of which have been kindly donated by people in the community. It would be great if visitors are inspired to look at things they would normally throw away with fresh eyes and find ways to be playful, perhaps giving objects a new lease of life. The ‘Up Your Street’ project has given me a wonderful opportunity to work in new ways in process and material; on a larger scale, and in an outdoor setting. I want to push the boundaries of how I use textiles and other media with the aim of what I hope is a positive impact on my local community.”</p>

<p><strong>Blooming Lovely</strong> will be on display from Monday 5th July to 31st July, Cavendish Road, Leicester. </p>

<p>The final piece is by artist Andy Harper and is called <strong>Leavings</strong>. This piece is an interactive installation built by the artist. Rubbish and litter from the local area will be repurposed into a sculpture that will be position in front of Andy’s house. The aims of this installation are to create an immersive & meditative environment that is accessible, fun and inspiring; whilst also challenging the neighbourhood and the wider community to consider the environmental impact that we are having on the planet. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_e6683a08c180451aa517241271777ed1~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>This installation responds to human interaction.  A proximity sensor will be mounted on a board at the front of Andy’s home which will trigger soundscapes which have been generated from recordings of the litter being cut, compressed, dropped, or manipulated. The intention is to emulate sounds found in nature - from the gentle blowing of the wind through the leaves to the song of a morning bird.  </p>

<p>On why he wanted to apply to become of the artists commissioned for Up Your Street, Andy said: “I spent parts of lockdown like many others walking around my local area and in the country.  I am very fortunate to live around the Charnwood Forest, however I found myself facilitating litter picks in the area during lockdown, as some areas
(particularly wild woods without access teams ) saw a sharp rise in traffic, which unfortunately resulted in more rubbish and fly tipping.  </p>
<p>
The installation will attempt to raise awareness to the issues that we have faced both culturally and environmentally.  Culturally, unlike other countries it feels like we are not as proactive at teaching future generations the correct outdoor etiquette from a young age.</p>
<p>
Environmentally - we are also guilty of creating and disposing of too much rubbish.  I hope that an installation built out of waste will raise awareness to the unsustainable way that we are collectively agreeing to live on this planet.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Leavings</strong> will be available for the public to see from Sunday 4th July- 31st July. And can be seen on Burton Street, in Loughborough. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>To find out more about the artists and Up Your Street, visit </strong><a href="http://www.vehiclearts.uk/" target="_blank" ><strong>,<u>www.vehiclearts.uk</u></strong></a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Up Your Street- Supported using public funding by the National Lottery through </strong><a href="https://www.artscouncil.org.uk/" target="_blank" ><strong><u>Arts Council England</u></strong></a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Sun’s Rising on Stunning Stories Hidden Around the City. ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sun Up, Rain Falls, River Rises is a beautiful storytelling project created by Journeys Festival International, the UK’s first Festival...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/the-sun-s-rising-on-stunning-stories-hidden-around-the-city</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60bf3a4fd42ac40015b095e3</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 09:48:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_275156fb496b47ee89032f47fccac474~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_500,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sun Up, Rain Falls, River Rises is a beautiful storytelling project created by <em>Journeys Festival International, </em>the UK’s first Festival of Sanctuary, in partnership with </strong><a href="https://www.phosphorostheatre.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Phosphoros Theatre Company</u></strong></a><strong>, Danish Composer </strong><a href="https://mirasiegelmusic.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Mira Siegel</u></strong></a><strong> and UK based illustration team </strong><a href="https://www.pickleillustration.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Pickle Illustration</u></strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a6c3b648ee5f44ba94e068c10e61b433~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7b15d6e58e854662bb827f0c1d0a5f78~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<p>Dotted around Rutland Water you will find a series of stunning posters that have been illustrated by Pickle Illustration. Each of the posters has been located in a specific spot for you to enjoy tales told by people seeking refuge in the UK. Scan the QR code on the posters and you’ll be whisked away to enjoy the stories from Eritrea, Sudan and Afghanistan. The locations have been carefully chosen to evoke the atmosphere of the narratives, enjoy The Dawning in the early morning, soak up the story behind After the Rain just after a downpour and take your time to delight in My Life as a River as you enjoy some time by the waterside. The posters link to some stunning artwork and an audio story, both of which are accompanied with a delightful musical score composed by the Danish composer Mira Siegel. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_c728df07b5cd4624a3746e6dd6cf5414~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_40d10ab21bc14964b73483703c2c8b9f~mv2.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_572fd757723a4f75a548ffe4585a0082~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_bb3918aa449b475293d973e5bd6dee0c~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_950f78ab21474f519fda938794d84fc8~mv2.png"></figure><p>At Rutland Water you’ll be able to enjoy these stories by simply scanning the QR code on each poster from 14-20 June as part of this year’s Refugee Week celebrations. You can find each specific location by visiting <a href="www.journeysfestival.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>www.journeysfestival.com</u></a></p>
<p>
Maddie Smart, Executive Artistic Producer for <a href="www.artreach.biz" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>ArtReach</u></a> and <a href="www.journeysfestival.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Journeys Festival International</u></a> said: “Mental health has really been brought to the forefront of everybody’s mind since the pandemic began and we’re hoping that taking some time to yourself, to enjoy these stories, will offer people a little mental respite from their daily chores. The stories, soundtrack and illustrations will allow people a chance to take a breather and be transported into a world far from their own. It’s easy to scan the codes at each location and we really hope that people will enjoy these little artistic insights into other people’s lives around the globe.” </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_275156fb496b47ee89032f47fccac474~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_500,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>For Refugee Week, Journeys Festival International is hosting a week's worth of events including live music, short films, dance and animation alongside the launch of a Global Kitchen recipe book, which features dishes from around the world for you to cook and enjoy at home.</p>
<p>2021 will be the 24th yearly celebration of the contributions, creativity and resilience of refugees and people seeking sanctuary. As the UK’s first Festival of Sanctuary<em>, Journeys Festival International, </em>offers a platform for refuge seeking artists to share their work to a wider audience so it’s great to see them offer a varied programme for us all to enjoy as part of this year’s celebration.</p>

<p><strong>You can find the locations for these wonderful stories, order a copy of the Global Kitchen recipe book and enjoy the rest of this year’s Refugee Week programme of events at </strong><a href="http://www.journeysfestival.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.journeysfestival.com</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Graeme Hawes Exhibition Celebrates Traditional Glass Making With A Contemporary Art Twist.]]></title><description><![CDATA[This June Graeme Hawes will showcase a brand new series of works at the Glasshouse Heritage Centre in Stourbridge. The exhibition titled...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/new-graeme-hawes-exhibition-celebrates-traditional-glass-making-with-a-contemporary-art-twist</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60bf35ab4ec5880015bb90c6</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 09:28:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1c7e5c0246e4450186210230e032a0b4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_884,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>This June </strong><a href="www.grhawesglass.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Graeme Hawes</u></strong></a><strong> will showcase a brand new series of works at the </strong><a href="https://ruskinglasscentre.co.uk/history-heritage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Glasshouse Heritage Centre</u></strong></a><strong> in Stourbridge.</strong></p>

<p>The exhibition titled “Modern Traditions” will show over 20 new art works, impressive in scale and skill. Inspired by the traditional glass blowing techniques and cutting decoration pioneered at the Webb Corbett and Stuart factories once a seemingly unstoppable West Midlands industry.</p>
<p>Graeme’s work celebrates glass, as a versatile material often thought of as purely functional, but Graeme’s skill with the material bridges that divide between traditional use and contemporary art highlighting the sculptural element of glass as an art medium.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1c7e5c0246e4450186210230e032a0b4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_884,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>Graeme Hawes has been a practicing artist for over 30 years receiving his training at the Royal College of Art. He has exhibited extensively across the UK, including shows at Vessel Gallery, Contemporary Applied Arts, Cecilia Colman Gallery, Somerset House, Saatchi Gallery and the Scottish National Gallery. His practice combines traditional handmade techniques with contemporary themes and approaches. Graeme’s interest in exploring colour theory and the use of glass within sculptural forms sees him experimenting with how materials can be used and developed aesthetically. He also explores the relationship between light and glass, looking at how faceted glass reflects, refracts, absorbs and projects.</p>

<p>This exhibition, which has been supported by Arts Council England, has allowed Graeme to really expand his art practice and collaborate with fellow master craftsmen. Working with Glass blower James Devereux, Graeme was able to create much larger pieces than in his usual practice. Alongside Richard Lambing and his staff at Redhouse Glass Crafts, Graeme was assisted by Nick Gritton, who was able to share his extensive expertise in glass cutting</p>
<p>techniques and patterns. The Stourbridge Glass blowing studios and Ian Bamforth have also provided support throughout the project. Assisting Graeme with facilities and manpower in creating his latest series of art works.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_21f53b318deb46b88d64cf7e7c5cfd75~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_884,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>Modern Traditions will celebrate the skills and traditions of the English glass industry by incorporating these traditions into a contemporary context. Graeme explains, “With this installation, I’ve taken a conceptual approach using irregular form and colour mixed with long-established cutting methods to make contemporary work that embodies the heritage of glass making. The pieces have strong visual impact as well as layered concepts, that encapsulate the history of the English glass industry and how its impact is still relevant today.</p>

<p>Graeme continues “I also want the work to challenge the traditional ‘craft’ label for glass that - in my view - has made it seem common place and has sometimes relegated the material to mere functionality or ornamental. I want to highlight the materials evolution into a contemporary art medium, as I feel these outdated descriptions do not do the material justice or credit the immense skill of the artists involved in its creation.</p>

<p><strong>Modern Traditions opens to the public 9th June and runs until the end of the month at </strong><a href="https://ruskinglasscentre.co.uk/history-heritage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Glasshouse Heritage Centre</u></strong></a><strong>, The Glasshouse, Wollaston Road, Amblecote, Stourbridge, DY8 4HF. Entry is free. </strong></p>

<p><strong>For more information about Graeme and his work please visit </strong><a href="www.grhawesglass.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.grhawesglass.co.uk</u></strong></a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arts &#38; heritage: working with museums for exhibitions and research ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Guest post by Ruth Singer, a professional artist and maker with a background working in the museum sector. Through her artist practice,...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/arts-heritage-working-with-museums-for-exhibitions-and-research</link><guid isPermaLink="false">609a53aca9d5540015ce180c</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:07:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f9ce5e9c175b4e5e9686bd5c9790103d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Guest post by Ruth Singer, </strong>a professional artist and maker with a background working in the museum sector. Through her artist practice, she has continued to work with museums, archives and heritage sites to research and exhibit. Read Ruth's introduction to her upcoming webinar on 18th May. </p><hr>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f9ce5e9c175b4e5e9686bd5c9790103d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Most of us would agree that museums, heritage sites and archives are really inspiring places. It can be very rewarding and creatively challenging to work with heritage in our creative practice. I’ve been working with, in and for museums for over 25 years and still find them endlessly fascinating and inspiring. Way back in the last century I spent my university holidays volunteering in museums to build up experience before my Masters Degree in Museum Studies. I helped out with Anglo-Saxon archaeology and goats, I sorted clothing at Nottingham Costume Museum, I cleaned books at Calke Abbey, I ran kids workshops on Ancient Egypt at Manchester Museum, I did guided tours for the National Trust, I sorted more clothing at Brighton Museums and eventually I started getting paid jobs doing curatorial and education work with a variety of collections from buses to medieval paintings (but no more goats). </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_36a41f8fd12a4276899b6e7e89c585d8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>After a decade or so working in curatorial & learning jobs, I decided to quit and set up my own creative practice, but maintaining my museum experience through working in partnership with heritage, archive and museum sites as an artist. Over the last 16 years, I think I’ve done (almost) every possible role for an artist working with heritage: I’ve run countless creative workshops, done talks and guided tours focussing on textile history, exhibited in group and solo exhibitions, been commissioned by museums to make work inspired by their collections, run my own research projects in archives and sold work to museum collections. </p>

<p>Museums and heritage collections are full of amazing things, both what you can see on display and more collections in store. There are temporary exhibitions to inspire and collaborate with, there are reserve collections, documents and other resources for you to explore in your own time and draw upon for your creative practice. There are displays of ceramics, plant specimens, clothing, tools, archaeology and human stories for you to delve into and fire your imagination. The majority of local museums in the UK are run by either trusts, charities or local authorities (councils and government) and most of them are set up with the aim of supporting learning which includes your creative inspirational development as an artist. Collections are there for you to learn from. In England, museums are due to reopen on 17th May and for a while will have time-ticketing and very spacious galleries.  In normal times, museums are usually happy for creative people to turn up and draw in their galleries, for hours at a time. Some sites and temporary shows may have limits to access times and ticketing so it’s worth checking first if they are happy for you to spend hours in there. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_8d2e4edcecfe4030acc786f5c9431f12~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_667,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you want to focus on one particular theme, object or subject, many museums have arrangements (in normal times) for research visits when you can ask to see particular items. Archives or Record Offices are really even better set up for this with reading rooms where you can order up documents and get them within an hour to read and explore. Many collections have online databases now so you can find out what they have and ask for what you want to see. </p>

<p>My upcoming webinar for WebinArt members will explore the ways you can work with museums from selling in their shop to exhibiting in their galleries and much more besides. I hope you will understand better how museums work, what they can and can’t do with and for artists, what you can access and how you can connect and collaborate to create amazing projects. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_42373b2cd8e2497fa6c648bed1a77be5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>WebinArt members can register for this event via the link in their calendar invitation. We hope you can join us!</p>

<p><strong>See more of Ruth's work here - </strong></p>

<p><a href="https://ruthsinger.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://ruthsinger.com/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/RuthSingertextiles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/RuthSingertextiles/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.co.uk/ruthsinger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.pinterest.co.uk/ruthsinger/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ruthsingertextiles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/ruthsingertextiles/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Setting Up A Creative Community, With Haarlem Artspace]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bev Shephard, WebinArt Mentor and Co-Director of Haarlem Artspace shares an introduction to the journey of Haarlem Artspace, and focuses...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/setting-up-a-creative-community-with-haarlem-artspace</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6087e6758ef5ed0032b8a9a5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:02:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_9e742bec01074f30b220b7032c5f6c1c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bev Shephard, WebinArt Mentor and Co-Director of Haarlem Artspace shares an introduction to the journey of Haarlem Artspace, and focuses on the importance of community being at the core of their purpose and growth.</strong></p>

<p>Haarlem Artspace champions rural contemporary art regionally, nationally and internationally through gallery and online exhibitions, residencies, publications, symposia, talks and events. With an ambitious annual programme of exhibitions, residencies and events, Haarlem Artspace attracts broad audiences to the historic town of Wirksworth, which sits in an inspiring landscape. Collaboration is at the heart of our work and through connections to a broad cultural network, we encourage the cross-pollination of ideas and facilitate inter-disciplinary knowledge exchange.</p><hr><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_0d3e157d23a648f995cf18e856216a3d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_615,h_922,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Our creative community’s home is in a beautiful historic grade II* listed building that is a sanctuary for our resident artists and makers. It’s an inspiring place to work with modern facilities and lively studio culture and community.</p>

<p>We have grown rapidly since we officially opened in May 2017 from a top floor studio with 11 people, to now 40 creatives over three floors, plus another handful of associate artists who are very much part of our community and have their studio at home. </p>

<p>We’re pushing at the limit of what the building can accommodate but rather than stop here, it’s bringing us to a place where we’re seeking to engage with the community outside of the studios, taking Haarlem Artspace to new audiences in new ways. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_9e742bec01074f30b220b7032c5f6c1c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>It has taken 6 years to get to this point though. Some of this was planned – we spent so much time on strategy in the early days in order to develop a clear vision of the future. Some of it has been revealed to us as the community has come together. The latter has what’s been such a pleasant surprise to me because I hadn’t anticipated the way people would get on board with the vision and lend their own unique strengths to help bring it about.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a7da7b1e886f41eca6eca00f9fa148a6~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Looking back, the right people in the right place with the right idea was what brought Haarlem Artspace together, and once we had formed the team, the organisation has grown into something none of us would ever have achieved alone. It now has its own identity and we hope, offers a distinctive lense through which it sees the world, sharing that with others through its exhibition and events programme.</p>

<p>Taking people with us on the journey has been so important. In the early days, we couldn’t access the building due to bat surveys, red tape and building work, so we had a choice – share our vision for what was coming, or wait until we could ‘start’ properly. We chose the former, and it turned out to be one of the best decisions we’ve ever made. Doing this brought the right people to us – both virtually with lively social media, and in person, in that the studios were full from opening and we had 360 people attend our opening from the local community. I don’t think waiting for an official opening would have had the same result.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f57ddf54c66041f08b7462cfe51d3f04~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>We also learned to understand that not everyone grasps the vision at the same time. Some people can't see the bigger picture until they see a space in the flesh. We had waves of take up, which worked beautifully for us as we expanded into the refurbished building one floor at a time. Not everyone comes to an idea at the same pace or same time.</p>

<p><strong>Bev Shephard</strong></p>

<p><strong>See more of what Haarlem Artspace do here -</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://haarlemartspace.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://haarlemartspace.co.uk/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/haarlemartspace" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/haarlemartspace</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/haarlemartspace/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/haarlemartspace/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr>
<p>WebinArt members can find out more about the journey of Haarlem Artspace from Bev and fellow Co-Director Livvy Punnett (2 or the 4 Directors) in our upcoming Webinar. Livvy Punnett is an artist, lecturer, cultural producer and curator. Bev Shephard is an independent Finance Director and business development consultant and both are founders and Co-Directors of Haarlem Artspace.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_59f1f3513b7e4962ab000735119bd097~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebinArt Member Focus - April 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce Clare Morgan, aka Curiousinkyme. WebinArt is...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/webinart-member-focus-april-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">607d8fe0293dec001506bb6e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 14:23:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_da586ce869964e40b227d0266665603b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce Clare Morgan, aka </strong><strong>Curiousinkyme.</strong></p>

<p>WebinArt is Creative Leicestershire's year-long professional development programme for creative businesses. Our Emerge members are early in their career and benefit from one-to-one tailored business mentoring sessions alongside a whole host of live online events and resources. </p>

<p><a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<strong><u>Click here to find out more about the WebinArt Programme.</u></strong></a> WebinArt 2020/21 is generously subsidised by our funding partners - Leicestershire County Council, Arts Council England, Derbyshire County Council, Hinckley + Bosworth Borough Council, North West Leicestershire District Council, Blaby District Council + Rutland County Council. </p><hr>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_da586ce869964e40b227d0266665603b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it. </strong></p>

<p>I am a fine art printmaker based in Derby, I create original, empowering portrait artwork that encourages reflection, empathy and calm using traditional screenprint and linocut techniques.</p>

<p>After graduating with a degree in Fine Art in 2005, I became a part of Green Door studios and fell in love with the printmaking process, I have worked using many techniques over the years. </p>
<p>I was drawn to the planning and creating of stencils and plates, it forces me to be patient, and I adore the element of unpredictability in the creation of the artwork. The thrill of the reveal when you lift the paper from the plate for the first time is addictive.</p>

<p>I also embarked on a career as an art teacher, and as my teaching responsibility grew my art practice started to take a back seat. In 2016 I was diagnosed with blood cancer, my work initially became a way of documenting this experience and I became fascinated with portraits, I made many self-portraits during this time as well as drawing from sitters at Derby sketching club as I recovered from a donor stem cell transplant. I made a commitment that my art practice would have more of a key role and I went part-time with my teaching and that’s where my practice in its current form began.</p>

<p>Initially, the artwork was a reminder to myself as I tried to hold onto my own lessons, but over time I learnt that it is a powerful way to encourage and connect with others. I started to meet people at art fairs and exhibitions and some shared their stories with me. I saw incredible strength and vulnerability and these connections reaffirmed the realities of the human experience that I passionately wanted to capture. I knew from that point that the human form was a vital part of the work. Artwork can be a powerful reminder of the things we see as important, makes us feel good and can be a talking point to help us build connections.</p>

<p>I am fascinated by Eastern philosophy, most recently Wabi-Sabi. This concept provides a way of defining the things I have always been drawn to in my art practice, it’s about acknowledging the incomplete, imperfect and impermanent, for me, this is accepting things as they are, and therefore being able to sit with the uncertainty. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_6d422f8c0a924719b68943af9820a899~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>

<p>My practice can ebb and flow over the year depending on the demands of teaching, I find that the times I’m not directly creating the ideas are forming in my mind and I get excited to be able to bring them to life. I always make sure I have at least 2 days a week working on my art practice and business. I have learnt (perhaps the hard way) that good studio organisation and specific workflows are vital, so I have processes set up for specific days to make sure that I am using my time well. I use an app called Trello to organise this, which has been a game-changer. I find time to get outdoors daily, and have taken up wild swimming over the last year, it is so important to have some balance and I find being immersed in nature is my way of being mindful and it keeps me creative and motivated.</p>

<p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>

<p>My main challenge has been the shift in my practice this year, which has also been the biggest success. I am on the UK shielding list so have spent most of the last year working from home, I would usually screenprint in a studio space where I could access specialist equipment and work on a larger scale.</p>

<p>Being at home I found that the scale and medium I chose needed to be appropriate to my attic studio space at home, that I could do with minimal equipment, so I ordered a couple of pieces of lino not knowing if it would go anywhere. The change in process has been the best thing I have ever done in my practice! It was definitely a learning curve finding my artistic voice in a new way, but I have found that it has allowed me to explore, experiment and push my ideas much further. The scale is much better too, allowing my collectors to curate their own gallery walls which have such an impact!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4e1be6da68054c80a6da6106738ef333~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_900,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>

<p>I would like to keep pushing the potential of lino cutting, perhaps combining lino and screenprinting when I can get back in the studio. I work in series, at the moment it is called ‘bloom’ and I am looking at this developing into a new series of work incorporating the seasons and the Japanese elements. In the long term, I would love to produce a body of work to apply to the royal society of painter printmakers and to be able to move to a bigger studio space. Teaching will always be a part of my practice as I love nurturing creativity in others and I can share my values and encourage others to work with curiosity.</p>

<p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>

<p>There are so many learning curves and challenges along the way, particularly the logistics of running a business, being able to access information is vital as it isn’t something that is covered in a creative degree. I have found the webinars and resources an invaluable source of information, and there’s such a variety and they focus on the essential things you do need to consider as a working artist such as pricing, writing copy, marketing, and even self-care. I came to the community a little later, but already everyone has made me feel so welcome and it is clearly such a supportive group, it is good to know that we are all figuring things out together and that there’s a wealth of information in the creative community.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_622f8461c6e64334a19943ce31d21ca0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong></p>

<p>Being outside in nature has been a source of inspiration, especially now it is spring. The blossom reminds me of new beginnings and makes me feel so optimistic. I enjoy wild swimming and being immersed in the lake is a place of inspiration, this just makes me feel so connected to my surroundings and this fuels my creativity.</p>

<p>I have recently been quite inspired by Romanticism, an art movement that was a reaction to order and rationalism. I love that it is spontaneous, imaginative and appreciates the beauty of nature, it favours the senses and reminds me of how I feel in those moments I seek out nature. </p>
<p>It was a reaction to the movement before (classism and neo-classism) as art often is, and I find it fascinating that it was seen as a bit of rebellion to want to connect with the natural world. </p>

<p>I recently read ‘the artists journey’ by Stephen Pressfield, I found it insightful and inspiring, it’s quite a philosophical look at the purpose of being an artist but there were so many parts of this that resonated with me. </p>

<p><strong>See more of Clare's work here - </strong></p>
<p><strong>Website: </strong><a href="www.curiousinkyme.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.curiousinkyme.com</u></strong></a> </p>
<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="www.instagram.com/curiousinkyme" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.instagram.com/curiousinkyme</u></strong></a> </p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="www.facebook.com/curiousinkyme2.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.facebook.com/curiousinkyme2.0</u></strong></a> </p>
<p><strong>Twitter: </strong><a href="www.twitter.com/curiousinkyme1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.twitter.com/curiousinkyme1</u></strong></a> </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Transforming Young People's Lives Through Creativity]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Mighty Creatives (TMC) is a charity based in the East Midlands and our vision is of a world where ALL children and young people have...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/transforming-young-people-s-lives-through-creativity</link><guid isPermaLink="false">606db83db76b9d00152f7313</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:15:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_47e75b265ce14ae1ac1c1f06993d07d5~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_777,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Mighty Creatives (TMC) is a charity based in the East Midlands and our vision is of a world where ALL children and young people have the opportunity to harness the power of arts and creativity to transform themselves, their communities and their future. Hazel Townsend, Development Manager at The Mighty Creatives, gives us an insight into the valuable work of the organisation.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>"We believe the arts and creativity is not a ‘nice to have’ but VITAL to support children and young people’s development. Sadly, many children and young people don’t have those opportunities and our work is increasingly focussed on supporting and empowering disadvantaged young people across the region – providing opportunities that can transform young people’s lives and contribute to the fight against child poverty.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>TMC are also Art Council England’s Bridge Organisation for the East Midlands – bridging the gap between children and young people and arts and creative opportunities in lots of different ways across the region including supporting partnerships, networks, training, resources and delivering Artsmark programme and Arts Award in the region.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_221d93299a064c5b8fd8b5eb680f465e~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p> </p>
<p>As a Development Manager at TMC and I lead our Artsmark programme – supporting approximately 400 schools across the region to develop their arts and cultural education. This gives me the opportunity to work with some amazing artists, arts organisations, schools,….. and most importantly, children and young people. Children are born innately creative beings - you only have to watch toddlers at play to recognise this - seeing them engage with creative activities without fear of being wrong….seeing their enjoyment……and seeing the how it can support their development.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Picasso famously said, “Every child is an artist. The problem is how to remain an artist once we grow up.” This remark has become a classic piece of advice to all creatives; it is a challenge to rediscover the wonder and creativity that is a natural part of childhood, and to bring that into your work as an artist. What better way to reconnect with your creativity than to work with children and experience art through their eyes?</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_47e75b265ce14ae1ac1c1f06993d07d5~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_777,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Many creative practitioner looks at sharing their skills with others, including young people, as a way of supplementing their income but it can also be a way of growing as an artist and discovering things about yourself and your practice that you’d never imagined!</p>
<p>…it can also be very inspiring. Over the last few months, TMC has celebrated <em>Keeping Art at the Heart</em>, highlighting the importance of arts and creativity, especially in supporting young people’s mental health and wellbeing. As part of this campaign pupils from four Artsmark schools worked with poet and rapper Mr Shay on the theme of ‘Art makes me feel’. </p>

<p>Here are some lines from the poem:</p>

<p><strong>Art Makes Me Feel.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Like a shark swimming in the depths of imagination.</em></p>
<p><em>Like a free bird soaring over mountains</em></p>
<p><em>Like a King building my own empire</em></p>
<p><em>The Queen of my own land,</em></p>
<p><em>I make the rules for myself.</em></p>
<p><em>Moulding them with my hands.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Art makes me feel hope .</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>It can be used to shift reality to your favour</em></p>
<p><em>Reassuring arms of repair</em></p>
<p><em>Not letting you fall into despair</em></p>
<p><em>Somewhere to look for</em></p>
<p><em>Someone you’ll know</em></p>
<p><em>Always a place for you to go.</em></p><hr><p>WebinArt members can find out more about our work at The Mighty Creatives and how to deliver and develop creative programmes and projects with young people by coming along to our webinar on Tuesday 13th April or by visiting our website – <a href="http://www.themightycreatives.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>www.themightycreatives.com</strong></a></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_808aa50af2f641d6a4fae8ee2b256e1f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[CHASING SEASONS EXHIBITION: THE EFFECTS OF CLIMATE CHANGE ON BIRDS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Leicester-based artist and former WebinArt member Lucy Stevens has been awarded an Arts Council National Lottery grant for her latest...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/chasing-seasons-exhibition-the-effects-of-climate-change-on-birds</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60508a7dd95546006daeaa08</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:44:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7ef8bc09bdc44daab12f07465db21134~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_708,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Leicester-based artist and former WebinArt member Lucy Stevens has been awarded an Arts Council National Lottery grant for her latest solo art exhibition, ‘Chasing Seasons’. The award will be used to explore the effects of climate change on bird species through a body of new mixed-media artwork.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7ef8bc09bdc44daab12f07465db21134~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_708,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Stevens’ exhibition will bring together art and science using a variety of creative techniques and skills developed at her art studio at StudionAme in Leicester.</p>
<p>
The project will see her working in collaboration with scientists and experts in the natural world from the British Trust of Ornithology and Leicestershire & Rutland Wildlife Trust. The creative process will include discussions with experts and access to bird-related research, case studies, and nature reserves to interpret the information in an accessible and creative way.
Visitors to the exhibition can expect to see a variety of new artworks, including vivid portraits of spring migrating birds, photographs of bird skins from Leicester Museum’s collections, and enlightening interpretations of scientific research.
</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_d74feffb2d5b44009646e04e9ee6661a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_708,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Peter Knott, Midlands Area Director for Arts Council England said: “Creativity has the power to help us explore the world around us, connect with nature and learn about our relationship with the environment. <em>“We’re really pleased to be supporting Lucy’s project through our National Lottery Project Grants and hope her unique work fusing scientific research and creativity will help inspire and educate those who experience it.”</em>
 
<a href="" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Professor James Pearce-Higgins, Director of Science from the British Trust for Ornithology said</strong></a><strong> </strong><em>“By watching birds, we can all see the impact that climate change is having on the natural world. The BTO harnesses those observations to tell scientific stories, for example showing much-loved migratory birds like the cuckoo and turtle dove are in long-term decline. In this exhibition, Lucy Stevens combines these themes to help us visualise the potential vulnerability of our long-distance migrants to climate change.”</em></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_ab55745673504e7dbef600744bf934b9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_708,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
Lucy said <em>"I am looking forward to collaborating with experts in the natural world who can provide insight into the decline of birds due to climate change and what this will mean for future species. This is a chance to delve into bird-related research and produce a creative response to demonstrate the importance of nature and our connection to it.”</em></p>
<p>
The exhibition will take place between Friday 7 - Thursday 20 May at StudionAme, 2 Brougham Street, Leicester LE1 2BA.  The exhibition will also be available to view online at <a href="http://www.lucystevens.co.uk/works/chasingseasons" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.lucystevens.co.uk/works/chasingseasons</u></strong></a> 
 
<strong>For further information visit: </strong></p>
<p><a href="www.lucystevens.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>www.lucystevens.co.uk</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/lucyjostevens/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/lucyjostevens/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/lucyjostevens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/lucyjostevens</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/lucyjostevens" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://twitter.com/lucyjostevens</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebinArt Emerge Member Focus - March 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce two talented creatives - Sarah-May...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/webinart-emerge-member-focus-march-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">604f5a743249a30015ea4f7b</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 16:27:42 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_8f10d89b171f47ccbbcd577722d8a9de~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce two talented creatives - Sarah-May Johnson and </strong><strong>Amber-Rose Bedwell</strong><strong>.</strong></p>

<p>WebinArt is Creative Leicestershire's year-long professional development programme for creative businesses. Our Emerge members are early in their career and benefit from one-to-one tailored business mentoring sessions alongside a whole host of live online events and resources. </p>

<p><a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<strong><u>Click here to find out more about the WebinArt Programme.</u></strong></a> WebinArt 2020/21 is generously subsidised by our funding partners - Leicestershire County Council, Arts Council England, Derbyshire County Council, Hinckley + Bosworth Borough Council, North West Leicestershire District Council, Blaby District Council + Rutland County Council. </p><hr><h2>Sarah-May Johnson</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_12150036348844499259a341a810c335~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_960,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I am a woven textile artist. My work is all carefully handcrafted on various table looms in my home studio. I enjoy pushing the limits of the loom to create abstract art pieces often inspired by the natural world.
</p>
<p>I have been creative from a very young age. I was always drawing, painting or making something as a child. This continued through college where I studied both art and textiles. I loved trying any creative process I could, however I remember being envious of my peers who had found their technique, or their style; The thing that was synonymous with them. Then at university I tried weaving. From the moment I first used a loom I was like "This is my thing: I'm a weaver!"</p>

<p>I had chosen to study textile design at university, thinking it would prepare me for a 'proper' job in industry, however when I was weaving I just wanted to push the limits of the process as far as possible in terms of material, texture and structure, making my weaving impractical for commercial use. I really wanted to pursue the process in an art context where practicality wasn't a restriction. This is exactly what I did during my Masters Degree and what I continue to explore now.
</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1db192b5078844df80e583c3a443210a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Until recently I was juggling making my artwork with a part time job as a print designer. I had managed to get quite a good work+work/ life balance. Unfortunately the print firm had to close due to the knock on effects of the pandemic. This change has been the nudge I needed to explore new avenues of my practice, for example running workshops, giving demonstrations and offering consultations on weaving and colour (all online at the moment). I have also acquired a new loom or two, with a view to hiring out equipment and offering one to one teaching of weaving. With the current lockdown restrictions there is very little else vying for my time and attention so I am able to really focus on my business. I feel so grateful to have my looms and all the equipment I need at home. Being able to throw myself into my work has kept me sane during lockdown.</p>

<p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>My main challenge was finding the courage to start on the journey to becoming an artist in the first place. After my masters degree I got swept into working in industry. First as a carpet designer, then as a digital print designer. Although I really wanted to be an artist I thought I should get a 'real job'.

Cut to 2018. All my close friends and I were turning 30, coinciding with each one accomplishing a big or exciting life goal or achievement. They bought houses, got married, had a baby, got a motorbike or landed a great job. When talking about what my turning 30 thing would be, somebody joked that I should quit my job and become an artist. That was it, the seed was sown and I couldn't forget about it. It took me a few months to pluck up the courage to go through with it, but at the very end of 2018 I handed in my notice and left the security of a full time job, to pursue my dream. 
</p>
<p>Since then I haven't looked back. I feel I am now on the path I should have been on all along. I had a few false starts, but once I figured out exactly where I was heading things started happening. I've started selling pieces and showing in exhibitions. My most recent success was finding out that I have just been accepted as a member of Design Nation. A few weavers who I greatly admire are also members. I can't quite believe that I'm now a member alongside them!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_8f10d89b171f47ccbbcd577722d8a9de~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>In the short term I have many ideas for pieces that I can't wait to make. I always have too many ideas and not enough time to weave them all. I also have plans to develop my workshops and consultation service as well as hiring out equipment. Each of these elements of my business are still in their infancy so there is a lot of work to do to get them off the ground.</p>

<p>My long term goals are to get my work into galleries in London, and other cities, and to work in a university. I worked as a brought in teacher and technical instructor for a short time. I really want to get back into that type of work. Not only do I love weaving, I also love teaching the process to others.
</p>
<p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>There are so many ways in which the WebinArt programme has helped me. It has provided all the practical business advice I was hoping to learn, such as how to approach galleries, manage finances, improve marketing strategies and much more. What I hadn' t appreciated before I signed up was the fantastic community of people I would get to know. I have met so many wonderful and supportive people and made so many friends. The programme has definitely expanded my knowledge on how to make creative business work as well as really boosting my confidence.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_9cd8de793fcf40ce817995b9a7419727~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong></p>
<p><strong>(List 3 things - This could be anything, such as an artwork, album or song, book, poem, essay, film or play.)</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>1 - Grayson's Art Club on Channel 4. During lockdown, when feeling a bit disconnected from people, this programme made me feel like part of a much wider community of creative people. Seeing what people from all over the country have been making and hearing Grayson, and his guests, be so animated and enthusiastic puts me in the mood for making things myself. Also Grayson and his wife, Phillipa are so kind and encouraging and fun together. That's my couple goals right there.
</p>
<p>2 - The Professional Weaver Podcast. I can't believe I only discovered this podcast a couple of days ago. I've just listened to a few episodes so far but they were brilliant. The type of podcasts that take all your attention and stop you from doing anything else (at least to a weaver. I realise it's quite a niche podcast). I learnt so much about two really inspiring weavers who I have admired for a long time.</p>

<p>3 - 'Do something pretty while you can, Don't be afraid'  Belle & Sebastian. This is my favourite song lyric. I have it written on a sign up on my wall. It isn't a new inspiration but something that I keep coming back to. I wish I had taken the advice and become an artist much earlier on. It also takes a lot of courage to be creative sometimes; to put brush to canvas, to try something new, to allow yourself the time to create.</p>
<p><strong>
See more of Sarah-May's work here - </strong></p>
<p><strong>Website: </strong><a href="https://www.sarahmayjohnson.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>https://www.sarahmayjohnson.com/</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/sarahmay.johnson/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>https://www.instagram.com/sarahmay.johnson/</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/5arahMayJohson" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>https://www.facebook.com/5arahMayJohson</strong></a></p>
<hr><h2>Amber-Rose Bedwell</h2><p>Amber-Rose Commissions</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_b091a66e0b704d218c74bc572309ebc3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_448,h_672,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>My name is Amber, and I am a pencil artist living in the very small county of Rutland. I</p>
<p>specialise in black and white portraits of people, working from photos that have been given to me. What give me such joy, is how precious each drawing can be to each of its owners. It’s like giving someone a snap of a memory, therefore making their own ‘moment in time’. This is why it is so important to me that I make each portrait as detailed as I can, as if it were</p>
<p>a photo.</p>

<p>Once finishing my two years at six form college, I jumped straight into full time work. This was mostly to later fund my countless driving lessons and three (yes three) driving tests. Nothing like determination hey! Inbetween working, I did the odd commission job or voluntary work, but nothing too substantial to make me think I could earn a living off. It has only been since the first lockdown all the way back in March, that I started to share pages from my sketchbook and found that people were interested in my work. Friends and family started to ask for commissions of loved ones for gifts or even as a treat to themselves. It’s crazy how sharing a few doodles you did to fill a bit of time in lockdown could lead to something far greater.</p>

<p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Due to the fact of working in a school, I get all the school holidays off (which at the time was</p>
<p>a massive selling point to an 18-year-old straight out of college) Therefore, since starting my</p>
<p>commissioned drawings, I’m lucky enough to have that extra time to balance my work and</p>
<p>my commissioned work. I try to take Sundays off for a bit of me time and to catch up on</p>
<p>other life responsibilities. But I usually find myself drawn (no pun intended haha) to my desk.</p>
<p>Because I leave work at four, I’m lucky enough to have the evenings so that I can crack on</p>
<p>with any current drawings. I’m so happy that the nights are starting to draw out, so that I can</p>
<p>eek out as much natural lighting as I can!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_3e85622ec43a4efdbc3967e01eb14247~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>A small challenge has been anything technology. From sharing posts to story’s on Instagram, to trying to put ink in my printer. It’s actually quite embarrassing how bad I am with technology, even more so as I’m only 22 years old! Thank god though, I’ve always got my boyfriend to hand. The number of times he’s saved a stressed out and confused girls bacon. If that ain't love, I don’t know what is.</p>

<p>My main challenge has been confidence. Many times, I’ve thought am I doing this right? Will</p>
<p>I actually get much out of this? I think because art is such a personal thing, you do feel like</p>
<p>you’ve put your heart a soul into every piece of work. You just want your work to be the best</p>
<p>that it can be, and even more so if someone is paying you for such a precious piece. Tied</p>
<p>into this though, is my success. I think my first ever commission was my biggest success.</p>
<p>Yes, I really under-priced and it took me weeks to complete because I was so het up on it</p>
<p>being perfect. But just that one sale and seeing it in someone else’s house made me realise</p>
<p>that yes, I do have a talent. After that I got the buzz to produce more.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f0952c10263d49a6b0bbbffeeb84fb68~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Of course, my main aim is to carry on producing commissions. Hopefully as I share more of</p>
<p>my work and through word of mouth, I can gain more commission enquires. That being said</p>
<p>I really need to start producing a website as another platform for people to view my work and</p>
<p>contact me (I’m sure my boyfriend can’t wait to help me out with that one)</p>
<p>In the near future, when life seems to be going back to normal, I hope to be doing art</p>
<p>classes in my local youth centre. I have been asked whether I would consider sharing my</p>
<p>skills to others, and leaped at the chance! It’s something new to try out and hopefully</p>
<p>another string to my bow.</p>

<p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>To be a part of WebinArt has been a really good opportunity. It’s a great platform to connect</p>
<p>with other artists in your area and also get inspired by what they do. During January I kind of</p>
<p>lost my mojo but made myself bad for feeling so. Having regular Creative Focus Meet-Up’s</p>
<p>made me realise that I wasn’t the only one feeling that way and that it was completely</p>
<p>natural. Just having a resource like this is so helpful to feel like you’re not alone through your</p>
<p>creative journey (especially during these unprecedented times) and that there is always</p>
<p>someone to help. The Webinars have also been very helpful, full of key information, tips and</p>
<p>even ideas to later explore.</p>

<p>I have also had the opportunity to meet my amazing 1to1 mentor Hazel. She has been</p>
<p>brilliant with boosting my confidence, and so patient to listen to all my ideas. After each</p>
<p>session we have together, I feel so much more positive and focused. She gave me the idea</p>
<p>to write down all my goals, even little ones (like buying a daylight lamp) and tick them off as I</p>
<p>complete them. Just the little act of ticking something off feels so good! It also makes you</p>
<p>realise just how much you have achieved in such a short period of time. I never knew that</p>
<p>finally getting round to buying a lamp could be so rewarding!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_ee67a3a512d84e1dbf1ae6875cf6e9d9~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has inspired you recently?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Due to the recent way we’ve had to adapt to life, I’ve found the small things a massive</p>
<p>influence. Take walking the dog. Not only has it been a needed hour out of the house, but</p>
<p>it’s also made me recognise what we are so lucky to have. Because I live in a very small</p>
<p>village, I’m lucky to be able to have open fields and tranquil spaces to notice the finer things</p>
<p>nature has to offer. If anything, I’ve learnt having a little time out is good for the sole. Another</p>
<p>really good resource has been ‘Good Vibes, Good Life’ by Vex King. I’m not one for</p>
<p>meditating etc, but this book has honestly made me view things through a different light.</p>
<p>Again, it’s made me appreciate the small things in life, and do everyday rituals that make me</p>
<p>smile. This leads me on to music, Ben Howard in particular. I listened to his music all the</p>
<p>way through my GCSE’s, In the studio at 6th Form, sitting at my desk drawing commissions,</p>
<p>and I’ll probably still listen to his music when I’m 80 let’s face it aha. I love just getting lost in</p>
<p>ambient acoustic sounds, whilst slowly developing my drawings. If you’ve never heard his</p>
<p>music, I highly recommend his album Every Kingdom. After all, who doesn’t like to get lost in</p>
<p>a good song?</p>

<p><strong>See more of Amber-Rose's work here - </strong></p>
<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/bedwellamberrose_art/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>https://www.instagram.com/bedwellamberrose_art/</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/bedwellamberroseart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>https://www.facebook.com/bedwellamberroseart/</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Establish Member Focus - February 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[This month we are sharing a conversation between member Rosie Ward (Smitten Knits) and our Establish group coordinator, Ruth Singer. They...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/establish-member-focus-february-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">603cb936e75c0a00410a4ee6</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 10:08:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_c22e7f738c554da083a7aa2b45f92cbb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This month we are sharing a conversation between member <strong>Rosie Ward (Smitten Knits)</strong> and our Establish group coordinator, <strong>Ruth Singer</strong>. They both create (very different) textile work and sell through various online platforms. The variety of methods for selling just go to show how complex the craft and textile market is. </p><hr><h2>Ruth singer, interviewed by rosie ward</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7be8996595a1492aa5ebdc1b0450dad8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_615,h_922,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Rosie: How has the lack of face to face markets impacted your business?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ruth:</strong> Luckily for me, I stopped selling at markets a few years ago so I haven’t lost that trade but I have lost out on exhibitions. Most of my work is created for solo or group exhibitions and sales alongside the shows in galleries and events (such as Festival of Quilts) has always been significant. The main impact has been a reduction in my marketing as well as sales because those events and exhibitions really helped to grow my profile which leads to more sales, commissions and invitations to exhibit and teach. </p>

<p><strong>Rosie: What methods have you used to help generate online sales?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Ruth:</strong> I do most of my selling via my online shop which is linked to but separate to my website (<a href="https://ruthsingerstudio.bigcartel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>I use Big Cartel</u></a>). I have also experimented with selling directly to <a href="https://www.instagram.com/ruthsingertextiles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>Instagram</u></a> followers and others using the Artist Support Pledge concept created by Matthew Burrows in the early stages of the pandemic. His idea was to create a hashtag (#artistsupportpledge) where people could see and buy work directly from the artist, while galleries and other places to sell were not available. The artist pledges that for every £1000 of work they sell under £200, they will spend £200 on works from other artists. I did one round of this last year and it went really well and I was so happy to have a reason to spend a fifth of my earnings on other artists. It’s great for everyone. So I will be doing this more in 2021 too. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_e7ee892c1a8143469836163abf3a6332~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_905,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Rosie: Do you hold stock of products you sell online or are all your pieces one-offs/made to order? </strong></p>

<p>I really only sell things that are already made. I do make to commission but I don’t really advertise this as it’s something I find quite hard as each piece I make is entirely unique with a personal story and antique textiles or tools. What I do have a lot of stock of is books, particularly my Criminal Quilts book which I self-published and have a large print run stored in my loft! I am trying to develop more digital products (techniques, patterns etc) so I don’t have the physical storage problems that come with print!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a467390ca7a9424fb93fbf6110bc9605~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a2b3159b1d1f4b019979ba22428b2343~mv2.jpg"></figure><p><strong>See more of Ruth's work here - </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://ruthsinger.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://ruthsinger.com/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/RuthSingertextiles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/RuthSingertextiles/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.co.uk/ruthsinger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.pinterest.co.uk/ruthsinger/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ruthsingertextiles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/ruthsingertextiles/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr><h2>Rosie WARD, interviewed by Ruth singer</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a1344e8d17af40a0acf15a5092c5bd68~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Ruth: Where do you sell online and how has each of those been for you?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Rosie:</strong> My main selling platforms are Not on the High Street, Etsy and my website (<a href="http://www.smitten.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>www.smittenknits.co.uk)</u></a>. The highest percentage of my sales come through Not on the High Street. I have had a good experience on there. They have a great support team who I have sought advice from on things ranging from product development to delivery issues. They have a huge online presence and are able to drive relevant customers to my storefront. </p>

<p>My experience with Etsy is that it has been more difficult to be found amongst the huge number of sellers on there. That being said there are many strategies that will help increase my visibility but I am still implementing these! They have a lovely community. </p>

<p>Over the past 6 months I have spent a lot of time working on my website as this is where I want to be driving most of my sales going forward. I have recently joined Amanda Perry's 'Ecom Growth Hub' after Amanda was highly recommended by Chloe Hardisty (founder of Cotton Clara) on her WebinArt event a few months ago. I'm so excited about this!!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_c22e7f738c554da083a7aa2b45f92cbb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Ruth: Do you sell different things in different shops and can you see a variation in what sells where?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Rosie:</strong> I generally offer the same product ranges on all selling platforms. I sell more high price point items (my patchwork blankets) on Not on the High Street. Bespoke orders mainly come through my website which I think is down to a small business website feeling more personal than just being a store front on a larger site.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_18ee4075d7234f808685a76c326112e2~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_5080144fc3fe4048bbbf76a6b783dced~mv2.jpg"></figure><p><strong>Ruth: What has changed in the last year about how you sell your work?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Rosie:</strong> Since the first lock down last year I started making more sales through Instagram. I think people (including myself!) have been spending a lot more time scrolling social media which has been great for us online sellers! I started making wall hangings with knitted messages designed to be 'letter box gifts' to send to loved ones whilst we were unable to see them in person. Each time I posted these on my Instagram I would receive messages requesting lovely personalisations on the wall hangings to be sent to friends and family which really made me smile.</p>

<p><strong>See more of Rosie's work here -</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.smittenknits.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.smittenknits.co.uk/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/smittenknits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/smittenknits/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/smitten_knits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/smitten_knits/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to: Reimagine a Live Event Online]]></title><description><![CDATA[Written by Heather Tyrrell, AKA Tricity Vogue. Heather is a writer, performer, producer, and musician. Her eclectic professional...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/how-to-reimagine-a-live-event-online</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6034ec0c3e5235001744c329</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:28:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_60d792ea56e64b76bb30cd1bb54964cf~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Written by Heather Tyrrell, AKA Tricity Vogue.</strong> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_60d792ea56e64b76bb30cd1bb54964cf~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Heather is a writer, performer, producer, and musician. Her eclectic professional portfolio includes ten years in television and another ten in cabaret. As a television script editor, scriptwriter and development producer she worked on shows including Teletubbies, Holby City, and My Family. Her time as Story Editor for children's programme Byker Grove was her favourite TV job. As cabaret performer Tricity Vogue she's taken five hit shows to the Edinburgh Fringe, and runs several long-running London cabaret nights. She fronts the 9-piece Tricity Vogue's All Girl Swing Band, who sell out iconic London venues including Wilton's Music Hall.</p><hr><p><strong>It's March 2021 and I haven't performed live on stage for a year.</strong> If you'd asked me twelve months ago what I did, I would have said “I'm a cabaret performer, I play ukulele and I have an All Girl Swing Band.” Like all musicians, that description of what I do feels a bit historical right now – my band gigs have all been cancelled or postponed and we won't be back on stage together until July 2021 (fingers crossed). But I have still put on cabaret shows and performed on ukulele since last March – just not in the same room as my audience.
</p>
<p>The plan was, last spring when the WebinArt team settled on my webinar and blog post for this year's programme, that I'd be talking about running live events. But how can I talk about something I haven't done for a year?</p>

<p>So I'm going to talk about the alternative that's been my and many other creatives' reality since Covid came along: running events online instead of in a live venue. I've talked to a few friends and colleagues in different creative fields about their adventures moving events and shows online over the last year, and I've gathered my thoughts about my own experiences. If you're planning some online events, or thinking about blending both online and live content for your own projects, I hope there'll be some useful steers to be had from our insights.
</p>
<p><strong>I asked four fellow creatives, and myself, nine questions. Here's a sample of the answers. I'll cover more in my webinar, when I'll be able to respond to your questions too.</strong>
</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_d2ffce6366a14b379578e8506c1eb093~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_463,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Pictured: James Millar’s Zoom “teletypes"</p>

<p>Question 1:</p>
<p><strong>What previously live events/experiences have you moved online in the last year, because of Covid 19?</strong></p>

<p>"I've taken Zoom-based portraits using the Victorian wet plate collodion process, as I've not been able to have my subjects physically in the studio. I called them “teletypes”. The process creates an image on a sheet of glass or metal with a large-format camera, developed on site. The camera is trained on my laptop screen. It needs a longer exposure – the subject has to stay still for up to a minute. But it's still live. I've also been making digital tintypes. People send me a digital file and I photograph the screen and make a print on metal or glass."</p>

<p><strong>James Millar</strong></p>
<p>Analogue and digital photographer. The Tintype Studio, his bespoke 'wet plate' analogue photography studio and dark room opened this year near Melton Mowbray in rural Leicestershire.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thetintypestudio.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.thetintypestudio.co.uk/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.jamestmillar.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.jamestmillar.com/</a></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_69f2318254a74a7eb3d98bab57a7d0be~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_426,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Pictured: Tricity Vogue</p>

<p>Question 2:</p>
<p><strong>Have you created entirely new digital content in response to Covid 19 restrictions, rather than simply moving a live event online? If so, can you briefly describe it?</strong></p>

<p>"A new ukulele group started in March 2020 at the instigation of fellow-performer Sarah-Louise Young, who gathered together a group of performers and theatre-makers interested in learning ukulele, and asked me to teach them. The “Keen Beans” have been meeting weekly ever since, and are still going strong as a social support network through the pandemic, as well as a focus of musical practise, and have expanded to include a number of my former students from other workshops and classes I've taught. The group take turns to suggest songs they'd like to work on – old favourites, new discoveries – and we spend time talking about the associations the songs carry for us, as well as what's going on in our own lives, alongside actually playing some music."
</p>
<p><strong>Heather Tyrrell, AKA Tricity Vogue</strong></p>
<p>Cabaret performer, ukulele player, singer-songwriter, All Girl Swing Band leader, musical theatre writer, novelist, journalist, former television writer and script editor.</p>
<p><a href="http://tricityvogue.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://tricityvogue.com/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://heathertyrrellwriter.wordpress.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://heathertyrrellwriter.wordpress.com/about/</a></p>

<p>Question 3:</p>
<p><strong>Has the online content you’ve created sustained you on a par with the live events you previously ran – financially and/or creatively? Have you found a way to make a financial and/or creative model work online for you?</strong></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_90fc524bc1e643b0acab3019564f01bc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_480,h_601,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>"I definitely miss a live audience. There is an energetic exchange which is missing. It’s like suddenly losing your sense of smell. My instinct to read a room and respond can’t function as it did. I’m used to improvising and shaping my material around an in-the-room response. However it has been very satisfying to reach different audiences and even do a live broadcast for a theatre in the US. Financially I have had to work twice as hard for half the money but I am grateful I have found ways of earning. I’m teaching more than I was and also launched a bespoke songwriting service. I haven’t really been drawn to social events online (partly due to screen fatigue and partly because large groups of people staring at each other aren’t my idea of fun)."</p>

<p><strong>Sarah-Louise Young</strong></p>
<p>Actor, singer, writer, cabaret performer, teacher, theatre-maker</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sarah-louise-young.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.sarah-louise-young.com/</a></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_63e059de27a64e5891e7691c607c99de~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_639,h_480,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Pictured: James Millar’s Zoom “teletypes"
</p>
<p>Question 4:</p>
<p><strong>What elements of your formerly live events have proved irreplaceable? What, if any, elements have you found online alternatives for?</strong></p>

<p>"Most of it really, other than the Zoom “teletypes”. The entirety of what I do cannot be moved online. I've got to be physically at an event to photograph it, or have someone physically in my studio. There's only really landscape photography left. Online alternatives can only be very limited.</p>
<p>There've been fun parts. The Zoom portraits have taken me all over the world to Las Vegas, Sri Lanka, Liege and LA. I wouldn't have seen or spent time with those people without lockdown.</p>
<p>It's also been an interesting positive experience from a creative point of view, as a collaboration with the subject at the other end – how the subjects light and frame the portrait is up to them."</p>

<p><strong>James Millar</strong>
</p>
<p>Question 5:</p>
<p><strong>What practical challenges, pitfalls and solutions have you encountered?</strong></p>

<p>"Sound has been tricky. Facebook Live is great but even with Original Sound activated Zoom still compresses. Lighting is king. I’ve started to use an ethernet cable in case of poor wifi. Jamkazam is the closest we’ve got to getting rid of a time delay for rehearsals when two musicians are in different places but I wouldn’t trust it for a show. Neighbours have sometimes complained too, but now I give them warning!"</p>

<p><strong>Sarah-Louise Young</strong>
</p>
<p>Question 6:</p>
<p><strong>Have any unexpected silver linings or fringe benefits emerged from running online events?</strong></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_a7c2f224603a431b9a4b9a67f771dc36~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_427,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>"Our flagship event is an art exhibition where we usually get 100-150 people through the door – our online equivalent got over 500 visitors. I did not see it coming and am still shocked by the numbers. I’ve really enjoyed the pivot to online working – it has opened up so many new avenues of working, I have upskilled and learned new programs which has helped my personal development. It changes your way of thinking and potentially the events industry for the future."</p>

<p><strong>Kelly McCormack</strong></p>
<p>Kelly is an Event Manager for the University of Leicester, Film Producer for GM Finney Productions, Performer for Skytribe Studios, Director of Social Enterprise Iconic Music Dance Drama Ltd, and Trustee for Voluntary Action Leicester. In 2019, Kelly won the East Midlands Women’s Award (EMWA) Outstanding Woman in Arts, Media, and Music.</p>
<p>(I had the pleasure of mentoring Kelly in last year's WebinArt scheme!)</p>

<p>Question 7:</p>
<p><strong>Will you continue your digital offerings after Covid restrictions are lifted? Why/why not?</strong></p>

<p>"Yes I think so, as it’s nice to teach/facilitate people that live all round the country/world!"</p>

<p><strong>Emma Waterford</strong></p>
<p>Emma is a performer, arts facilitator, co artistic director of <a href="https://www.crowsnesttheatre.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crows Nest Theatre Company,</a> Associate Artist of White Rabbit and one third of <a href="https://www.thebluestockingsociety.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Bluestockings Society</a>. She regularly runs arts and crafts workshops with recent work focusing on bringing the arts to participants living in isolation</p>
<p><a href="http://www.emmawaterford.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.emmawaterford.com</a></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4195c0c8c19e4604b9bbf4b015c9d6c0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_427,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Question 8:</p>
<p><strong>What online events have you attended that you felt really worked, or didn’t, and why/why not?</strong></p>

<p>"Watched a live solo show that didn’t have enough bandwidth so you could either hear or see the performer but rarely both at the same time!"</p>
<p><strong>Emma Waterford</strong></p>

<p>Question 9:</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any tips for creatives planning online events or experiences?</strong></p>

<p>"It's good to reach out and connect with people for your own sanity and to keep the creative process going, keep your profile going, maintain the connections you made before covid came along. Keep trying to innovate and find ways around the restrictions we're under."</p>

<p><strong>James Millar</strong></p>

<p><strong>See what Heather does as Tricity Vogue here -</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://www.tricityvogue.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.tricityvogue.com/</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/tricityvogue" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.youtube.com/user/tricityvogue</u></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.facebook.com/tricityvogue" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>http://www.facebook.com/tricityvogue</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/tricityvogue" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://twitter.com/tricityvogue</u></a> </p><hr><p>WebinArt members can access our upcoming webinar <strong>'How to: Reimagine a Live Event Online' with Heather on 2nd March at 10am</strong>. During this webinar, Heather will dive into three golden 'how to's for creating online events -</p>

<p>1) How to: Dream up an online event that people want to participate in</p>
<p>2) How to: Troubleshoot in advance to avoid live mishaps</p>
<p>3) How to: Bring human contact into the digital realm</p>

<p>To learn more about joining WebinArt, click <a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u><strong>here</strong></u></a>. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_fd52ce28536044918488428c638c30d1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebinArt Emerge Member Focus - February 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce two talented creatives - Jo Morley...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/webinart-emerge-member-focus-february-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">601d10ee3befc20018b21c8e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_318dd19a74994427970dfaa8dccf17f2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce two talented creatives - Jo Morley and Emily Bird.</strong></p>

<p>WebinArt is Creative Leicestershire's year-long professional development programme for creative businesses. Our Emerge members are early in their career and benefit from one-to-one tailored business mentoring sessions alongside a whole host of live online events and resources. </p>

<p><a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<strong><u>Click here to find out more about the WebinArt Programme.</u></strong></a> WebinArt 2020/21 is generously subsidised by our funding partners - Leicestershire County Council, Arts Council England, Derbyshire County Council, Hinckley + Bosworth Borough Council, North West Leicestershire District Council, Blaby District Council + Rutland County Council. </p><hr><h2>Jo Morley</h2><p>Jo Morley Art</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_42a479ee2169456aa6ff163398dc9461~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_983,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I started painting again seriously about 3 years ago (after just dipping in and out of art since school). I didn’t study Art (I did Music at Uni) but found that I was always drawn to it in one way or another. I initially dabbled in digital art but wanted to do more traditional painting, and found I had a knack for portraiture and realism, and I really enjoyed creating physical paintings.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>It’s only recently that I’ve decided to spend more time on it, and focus more on my practice and establishing myself as an artist. I’m still finding my feet but I’m learning more as I develop.</p>
<p> 
</p>
<p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>This is the hard part! I work part time for the NHS so I’m always kept busy, and have two younger children, so I don’t get to paint as often as I’d like, at the moment mainly evenings and snatched hours at the weekend. Of course there is not just the painting there’s the admin/ marketing/ web aspect to it. I’ve tried to set aside certain times, and I’ve always got my next painting (or few) planned out. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>I’m also on the committee for my local art group, I’m both Exhibition Secretary and Web/Social Media Secretary and I’ve been quite busy of late sorting out a virtual programme on our website. This is also giving me skills I can use in my own practice for example I’m currently applying for funding for the club, so I’m hoping to get the experience of that process.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f82dfe791f0848839fbbdb9d18234e1b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I think my main challenge is time, fitting it all in (see previous answer!), I think it’s also a lack of confidence as I’m just starting out. I have a bit of imposter syndrome, and need to have a bit more confidence in my skills. I also struggle a bit with motivation sometimes, but don’t we all! It’s been especially hard with changes in routine that this past year has bought.</p>
<p>I think my biggest success has been this past year getting into the Harley Open. It really boosted my confidence and it’s also nice to hear positive feedback about my work. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4cfd963ea1774bea93dbd9b3d37463c5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Short term, I’m dropping a few hours from my day job to really focus my time and concentrate on my practice, and maybe get a few more commissions under my belt. I’d also like to try a few more open competitions as I sometimes need that deadline! Long term, I just want to keep creating paintings, enjoying the process and hopefully earning a bit of money as I go along.
</p>
<p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I am finding it really beneficial. I’ve watched a few of the older videos and catch up with ones I can’t attend and I’m learning so much, getting so many tips. My mentor Paul is also great, he’s really helped with learning about pricing my work (which was an area I knew nothing about!) It’s really helped me to see where I should be focussing my efforts and having a network of like-minded creatives has been really inspirational!</p>
<p>
</p>
<p><strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong></p>
<p><strong>(List 3 things - This could be anything, such as an artwork, album or song, book, poem, essay, film or play.)</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I usually listen to an audiobook while I paint, and recently listened to Mudlarking by Lara Maiklem. It sounds fascinating, all of that history at your feet (if you can find it) history is another passion of mine and I love the stories, and the aesthetics behind the objects. I’d love to do it a friend of mine does and finds wonderful things, but knowing my luck I’d probably get stuck in the mud!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I also read “A Face to the World: On Self-Portraits” by Laura Cumming. An insight into some of the world’s most famous self-portraits and the lives of those behind them. A great insight, which has made me think more about the work I produce, and what my paintings can reveal about the sitter.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I also recently rewatched “I,Claudius” (I didn’t see the original broadcast, but watched it about 15 years ago), such an addictive watch and great cast. It’s not exactly HD, but you get past that as it’s such a great story. </p>
<p> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_318dd19a74994427970dfaa8dccf17f2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>See more of Jo's work here - </strong></p>
<p><strong>Website: </strong><a href="www.jomorleyart.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>www.jomorleyart.co.uk</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/jomorleyart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>https://www.instagram.com/jomorleyart/</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/jomorleyart" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>https://www.facebook.com/jomorleyart</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p><hr><h2>Emily Bird</h2><p>QuirkEBiRD</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_806684c49e12424c99194a6916b94da4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Hi everyone! I’m Emily & I’m a mixed media artist, designer and teacher from Leicestershire. I like to create fun, colourful and contemporary designs inspired by the general goings on in every day life. I often combine my illustrative style drawings with hand cut paper techniques, paint and print and hope to throw in a bit of quirky humour along the way!
 
After completing my degree in Fine Art many years ago, I stumbled through a number of jobs (including working in Ann Summers, which my dad was mortified about! haha) before embarking on my teaching career which has lasted 17 years to date. However, a few years ago I decided I’d had enough of the job taking over my life and was desperate to find time to explore my own creative impulses, so I left the school I loved to become a supply teacher. The only downside is I don’t just teach Art & Design, I now have to teach EVERY subject.... including maths!!
 </p>
<p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The positive side to being a supply teacher is that I can select the days I’m available for work on a weekly basis, so I’m able to work around family life. Every spare minute I have between the usual joyous jobs of being a mother entails, I get down to being creative and generally making a mess all over the kitchen! (I do actually have my own ‘Arty’ Room but I seem to have a magnetic pull towards the main room in our house....much to the annoyance of my husband! )</p>
<p>Multi-tasking is key to making progress for me! I find it easier to have several things on the go at once so you’ll probably find me knocking up a spag Bol, whilst cutting out birds feathers and developing a commission! Its amazing what you can do with a spare half an hour!</p>
<p> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_73bb4473bbc94f1d940386b5813a894e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Where do I start? Well anything involving technology is always a challenge for me, unless its a PowerPoint...I’m quite a dab hand at those! I’m literally stuck in the 80’s and much prefer to rely on/trust  the old pen and paper so needless to say I haven’t explored Photoshop yet! (but its on my list. Quite far down but it’s definitely an area I’d like to look into).</p>

<p>Marketing myself I have found awkward and somewhat challenging. I guess self-doubt & being a bit of a perfectionist come into it and I don’t feel at all comfortable ‘selling myself’. (I’m likely to have more success selling vibrators!) However,  Instagram has really given me the opportunity to get my work seen and it’s been great to also see and take advice from lots of other inspirational people.</p>

<p>I guess I have lots of little successes to be pleased about and every sale is great obviously! I’ve had work selected for the SOCK and Ferrers galleries over the years and have very recently been approached by Wistow gallery to supply them with an exclusive series of paper cut designs. I’m really excited about this as I love this rural gallery and they really do support and promote lots of local talented makers. I also created a  quirky pub illustration of my village (we have a lot of pubs!) last year which was so popular I had to double my print order!</p>
<p>Having too many ideas is also a hurdle I stumble upon often! I need to learn to be more selective with what I choose to take forward and develop and not feel the need to do everything! (some of the ideas aren’t that good! Haha) Hmmm, I should remind myself of this every once in a while!</p>
<p> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_b010d639a08b475e98de846f6d59cb04~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Well I’ve always loved to draw. I’m really loving the illustrative side to my work so I’m planning on developing a series of drawings I started years ago and picked back up last year in lockdown. I’m planning to combine these with my love of paper and a touch of humour based on every day events and I’m hoping to take these into cards/prints.</p>
<p>I’d really like to continue to explore my paper cut designs also and challenge myself with some bigger and more detailed creations that I may be able to exhibit.</p>

<p>Now that I’ve finally managed to set up an Etsy shop, I must focus some time to add more designs and try to make my passion become financially viable. Once we are able to return to ‘normal’ (whatever that will be) I would like to start up some creative workshops for kids and adults focusing on a variety of skills and techniques.</p>
<p> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_794fae8139334bfa97ad91df81bb69ec~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Being part of the WebinArt programme has been great! Its given everyone involved an opportunity to connect with other like minded creative people from a varied range of disciplines. The webinars have been so informative, full of really useful advice and encouragement. It’s been really inspirational to hear success stories from other artists too and how their journeys have un-ravelled. There’s hope for us all!</p>

<p>I have been lucky enough to be teamed with the lovely Martha (the Stitch Writer) as my mentor this year. Her wonderfully warm and friendly approach made me relax immediately. She has been an ear to patiently listen (and I probably did waffle way too much in our first chat!) and a figure of encouragement and positivity. Her advice to “just do it!” is something I now say to myself all the time. Things don’t always have to be perfect as long as you take that step...perfection can come later!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>What has inspired you recently?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Inspiration has been everywhere in the last year! Whether it be an interesting podcast, entertaining, light hearted Netflix series (Yep, ‘Bridgerton’ was right up there) or one of the many ‘heroes’ of the pandemic. There has been so much to take inspiration from. Being at home so much and limited to activities, its made us slow down and appreciate the beauty of nature and what we have at our finger tips. I’ve been lucky enough to have time to read more, (‘The Salt Path’ was truly moving) listen to old 80’s hits and reminisce on life. Homeschooling is not inspirational though.... but that’s another story!  </p>

<p><strong>See more of Emily's work here - </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/QuirkEBird" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/QuirkEBird</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/quirkebird/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/quirkebird/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/QuirkEBird" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/QuirkEBird</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Community Art in a time of Coronavirus]]></title><description><![CDATA[Written by Paul Steele, Managing Director of Junction Arts. Junction Arts has been delivering community arts programmes in disadvantaged...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/community-art-in-a-time-of-coronavirus</link><guid isPermaLink="false">601ad1c8124da0001747da50</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 17:08:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1c9d4fd40af94b3fa08de3c3a73ce642~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_960,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Written by Paul Steele, Managing Director of </strong><a href="https://junctionarts.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Junction Arts</u></strong></a><strong>. Junction Arts has been delivering community arts programmes in disadvantaged communities for over 44 years. They help communities facing social barriers such as poverty, poor health, and low aspirations to create a better future through the arts.</strong></p><hr>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_609ae44b700e43bd900e3e8dba2f2163~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>We have all seen how important creativity and culture have been over the past year. Whether you’ve immersed yourself in a good book or TV box set or have escaped into your favourite music, culture has been our reliable friend, a welcome distraction and a familiar comfort in a difficult year. Alongside culture, people have found new ways to be artistic at home and there has been a creativity boom. There are many reasons for this but ultimately as human beings we want to express ourselves and there is no better form of self-expression than through creativity. </p>

<p>At Junction Arts we have been championing the vital role that arts participation can play in all our lives for over four decades. We believe the arts are for everyone and individuals and communities can build a better future through the arts. This vision is ambitious and idealistic but we’ve witnessed first-hand how participation in the arts can change a person and bring a community together. We usually work in a specific ‘place’, co-creating projects and events with local people, developing creativity from the ground up that has a long-lasting impact on the people that take part.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_ce200b163ebe41e694d72ef66218c80f~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_0f9ed0d157e0407ea4bf4b694ed7ace1~mv2.jpg"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1c9d4fd40af94b3fa08de3c3a73ce642~mv2.jpeg"></figure><p>We believe the arts can give people a ‘voice’, develop confidence, skills and aspirations, bring communities together and give people opportunities and purpose. The ‘Creative Health Report’ (2017) produced by the All- Party Parliamentary Group on Arts, Health & Wellbeing evidenced how the arts can help meet major challenges including ageing, long-term conditions, loneliness and mental health, with 82% of people taking part in arts activities from deprived communities enjoying greater wellbeing. It also evidenced how community-based arts activities help children and young people explore identities, improve self-esteem and increase coping strategies. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4a77ae330f7d430198577cc79fa68842~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>Ultimately the arts give us a space to make sense of the world, which is probably why they were so important in 2020. When there is so much disruption and uncertainty in the world the arts can be used as a vehicle to process and legitimise our feelings. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_f2db5a055b0f4e56b1da49c0f259b0e8~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_480,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Like so many others we had to innovate and adapt our programme in 2020. Our focus was to ensure we continued to support health & wellbeing by helping people be creative, keep learning and stay connected. As a response we developed a range of initiatives that kept people connected through creating participatory artwork. The artists that we work with have also had to adapt to alternative ways of delivery. The foundations of community/participatory arts are based on physical connections. The process of participation and creating the artwork is just as important as the artwork itself. To re-create that ‘at-distance’ is fraught with conflict and tensions about what a participatory experience actually is. However, we did it, working with our artists we distributed ‘Curiosity Boxes’ to primary schools (including art and tech materials), encouraged people to post poetry about their ‘place’ on a virtual map, linked together 5 care homes and 10 isolated individuals through a series of online workshops and delivered our annual Bright Winter Nights festival using Click & Collect, artist surgeries and recreating a parade on social media. The innovation from creatives and artists to ‘find a way’ and keep going was incredible and the response from our communities was even more incredible with over 4,500 people engaging with our programme last year. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_855aab38a9af4e008810a92445e00639~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_709,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>So, it is with a renewed confidence that we move forward into 2021. The community arts sector was tested and traditional methods of delivery became irrelevant, yet we never stopped delivering. Bringing people together through creativity thrived because above all else people wanted to be creative! More than ever before we feel vindicated that community arts is just as important now than it has ever been, and as we emerge from a post lockdown world it will become more important as a way to try and make sense of the world. Culture and creativity were at the heart of surviving 2020 and culture and creativity will be at the heart of recovery in 2021. </p><hr><p>WebinArt members can access our upcoming webinar <strong>'How to Approach Community Arts Programmes' with Junction Arts on 9th February at 6pm</strong>. During this webinar, Paul will outline Junction Arts approach to community arts delivery and the key elements to a successful community arts programme. You will learn - how to develop a ‘place-based methodology’, the importance of ‘process’ and how co-creation can be embedded at all stages of the programme, including the Evaluation. </p>

<p>To learn more about joining WebinArt, click <a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u><strong>here</strong></u></a>. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_70fc8a1400d447eabff2dc5f00f3eb3f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>See more of the work that Junction Arts do here - </strong>
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://junctionarts.org/&#38;sa=D&#38;source=calendar&#38;usd=2&#38;usg=AOvVaw3UmqsnZOnd1QlPvYH290bt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://junctionarts.org/</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.facebook.com/junctionartsuk/&#38;sa=D&#38;source=calendar&#38;usd=2&#38;usg=AOvVaw3meH6Cdfkz9d1WCvZI2jLr" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.facebook.com/junctionartsuk/</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://twitter.com/JunctionArtsUK&#38;sa=D&#38;source=calendar&#38;usd=2&#38;usg=AOvVaw2tz2rI8mydQ8fjvVivAY0B" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://twitter.com/JunctionArtsUK</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.instagram.com/junctionartsuk/&#38;sa=D&#38;source=calendar&#38;usd=2&#38;usg=AOvVaw2Oqv9YVzE85nFkA6dNi8IH" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.instagram.com/junctionartsuk/</u></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHECRG1Se3GT1vCA0jQzPPg&#38;sa=D&#38;source=calendar&#38;usd=2&#38;usg=AOvVaw1CmA3hECmv7U_J-0EmVgQr" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHECRG1Se3GT1vCA0jQzPPg</u></a></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Establish Member Focus - January 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[Every month we feature some of our Establish members and ask them to interview each other about their work. This month Sophia Kyprianou...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/establish-member-focus-january-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">601151c82a52ba0017dadbf1</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:06:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_72831836bdf049249080403b3e0f77df~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every month we feature some of our Establish members and ask them to interview each other about their work. This month <strong>Sophia Kyprianou (aka The Curator-Educator)</strong> and <strong>Sharon Everest (aka Modflowers)</strong> focus on marketing and how they get their work out there. They do very different types of work so have contrasting ways of sharing their work to their specific audiences. Our Establish members often get together to discuss marketing and sharing their work as this is one of the most challenging and important aspects of running a successful creative business. </p><hr><h2>The Curator-Educator, interviewed by Modflowers</h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_d859b232ae79463e809b2de738a7305b~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_750,h_724,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>1. Tell me about what you do, why you do it and who it is aimed at</strong></p>

<p>My name is Sophia and I am the Director and founder of The Curator-Educator, a small creative business which is all about developing creative opportunities that are accessible, inclusive and diverse for individuals and communities and aims to encourage people to engage creatively on their own level through workshops, community projects and exhibitions. There are lots of creative things we do as a company, but our key focus presently is around providing creative opportunities that aim to improve people’s and community’s mental health and wellbeing, our biggest initiative being our Crafternoon: Creative wellbeing project. </p>
<p>The reason I do what I do, is that I genuinely believe in the power of art and being creative. I think it can break down barriers, provide opportunities, support people and for me can be accessible and inclusive for all, which is what we’re all about at The Curator-Educator.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_689179447e2d47b8a2307761c4bf82bf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_747,h_458,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>2. Have you had to adapt your practice and marketing during lockdown restrictions - what have you done / are you doing at the moment marketing-wise that you might not have done in the past? For example, I notice that you've been doing Facebook Lives recently - how do you plan and prepare for these and do they take a lot of courage to do?</strong></p>

<p>Since the outbreak of Covid-19 things have looked a little different for us at Curator-Educator HQ, as prior to the pandemic majority of our work was done face to face with the community and individuals, so we have had to become adaptive that's for sure. We have moved all our workshops online, and have learnt new technological things that definitely keep us on our toes! </p>
<p>It definitely has meant that our marketing has changed and evolved a lot since March, we have been more visible in the digital world and as you mentioned we have been running Facebook live videos for our crafternoon sessions. There is a fair bit of planning for the sessions behind the scenes, with planning what crafts we are going to make, materials needed and social media content for each session as we like to share our programme beforehand to give people time to get resources or for us to send resources to them. It was a little nerve wracking to begin with, but now running the sessions feels part of our work now. It can feel a little odd sometimes, as you are talking to yourself or to people you cannot see, and the challenges of internet connections can be frustrating, but we do our best and hopefully our sessions help people practice some creative self care in a small way. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_17e359628f9342438d874ffa01f12ecf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_750,h_919,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>3. What type or aspect of marketing do you enjoy most and what do you dislike about marketing - and why?</strong></p>

<p>I actually really enjoy the design aspect and creating content as part of our marketing strategy. I feel it's an opportunity to be creative in a different way and try different visuals and content with our followers online. Though, I must admit sometimes, I can get a little carried away and several hours can pass in the designing of things. </p>

<p>I think with marketing, the time it takes to put together and keep up with everything can sometimes be a frustration for me, but I’m always looking at new ways to create marketing and have found scheduling platforms to be really helpful and planning out content 1-2 weeks at a time can save a lot of time. </p>

<p><strong>Check out The Curator-Educator here - </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.sophiakyprianou.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.sophiakyprianou.com/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheCuratorEducatorLtd" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/TheCuratorEducatorLtd</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/thecuratoreducator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/thecuratoreducator/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p><hr><h2>modflowers interviewed The Curator-Educator </h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7212ff4f6bda41d99a25490b49e7e504~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_720,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>1. What do you do/ create/ make and do you use social media to share your practice?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>As modflowers I design and make art dolls and quirky decorative creatures from cloth and clay, often in miniature, using mainly vintage or upcycled fabrics. I've worked with designers to produce art dolls from their own fabrics and recently I've started making small bears, modelled on vintage teddy bears. </p>

<p>I share my work on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/modflowers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>Instagram</u></a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/modflowersUK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>Facebook</u></a> and <a href="https://www.pinterest.co.uk/modflowersUK/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>Pinterest</u></a>. </p>
<p>I love Instagram, because of its focus on beautiful images. I also like the feeling of community between fellow makers. I post to Facebook regularly, as I have a small but committed band of followers there. I use Pinterest more for pleasure than business, but it does help get more eyes on my work.</p>
<p> </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_259a4cf855fb4fcab39320856c7a22d5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>2. Have you tried any new marketing techniques / strategies for 2021?</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I have been trying to build my following and interaction on Instagram. I've been posting more regularly and researching useful hashtags by looking at what popular makers use in their posts. </p>

<p>I also started a mailing list last year and have been promoting this via a link in my Instagram bio and elsewhere. My work output is relatively small and I don't always have items on sale, so I ask people interested in buying from me to join my mailing list to be notified of when new work is available. Eventually I'd like to try using Patreon - but I need to develop what I can offer to supporters before I launch into it.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_72831836bdf049249080403b3e0f77df~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>3. Have you got anything creative coming up soon and how are you sharing it with people? (e.g. social media, newsletter, videos etc)</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I'm aiming to start a newsletter for my mailing list subscribers. I've been signing up to other makers' lists, to see the kinds of things they send out. I want people to feel that by signing up they'll get something from me other than just promotions! </p>

<p>I also have a <a href="https://www.modflowers.co.uk/blog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,<u>blog</u></a> on my website, which I used to write daily until I ran out of steam! I'm aiming to resurrect it and post weekly. I like writing stories, I just ran out of ideas for what to write about - time for some research to find out what people want to read!</p>

<p><strong>Check out Modflowers here -</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.modflowers.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.modflowers.co.uk/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/modflowersUK" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.facebook.com/modflowersUK</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/modflowers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>https://www.instagram.com/modflowers/</strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[WebinArt Emerge Member Focus - January 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce three up-and-coming creatives - Maria...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/webinart-emerge-member-focus-january-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6001618b30df00001798a753</guid><category><![CDATA[Creative Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Interview]]></category><category><![CDATA[WebinArt]]></category><category><![CDATA[Inspirational]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 12:09:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_713d1092fda74ca49a7af69bb2b07375~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>In this Emerge member focus blog post for the 2020/21 WebinArt programme, we are proud to introduce three up-and-coming creatives - </strong><strong>Maria Ross,</strong> <strong>Joss </strong><strong>McAuley and </strong><strong>Jessica Mannings.</strong></p>

<p>WebinArt is Creative Leicestershire's year-long professional development programme for creative businesses. Our Emerge members are early in their career and benefit from one-to-one tailored business mentoring sessions alongside a whole host of live online events and resources. </p>

<p><a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<strong><u>Click here to find out more about the WebinArt Programme.</u></strong></a> WebinArt 2020/21 is generously subsidised by our funding partners - Leicestershire County Council, Arts Council England, Derbyshire County Council, Hinckley + Bosworth Borough Council, North West Leicestershire District Council, Blaby District Council + Rutland County Council. </p><hr><h2>MARIA ROSS</h2><p>URGHH Designs and Riia Ross</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_55072e87a9eb4f2c9c40fff9abc5cc09~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>

<p>I started embroidering as a hobby after graduating in footwear design in 2016. After selling at a few craft fairs in Leicester, URGHH became a big passion project where I began to sell a wider range of products! Eventually I started focusing the business on quirky and rude greeting cards and prints.</p>

<p>Riia Ross is now my creative outlet for original illustrations and prints, embroidery pieces and possibly sculpture in the near future! 

<strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong> </p>

<p>I’m a night owl so I usually draw and craft right into the early hours. Luckily, my day job isn’t 9-5 so I can roll with it and create in my spare time.

<strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>

<p>My main challenge has probably been getting my head around marketing. When you don’t have experience in it, you feel like you’re being annoying by plugging your work but you just have to keep at it. I’m at a point now where I really enjoy interacting with followers and sharing my work so I’ve definitely learned a lot! The way I photograph my work has come so far as well so that has come with a lot of practice and seeing how others present their work!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_df63fe7d41564fdb8832f2540e2d17a0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>

<p>My plan for URGHH is to have my cards and prints stocked in shops throughout the UK and eventually worldwide! I’d also love to collaborate with some of my favourite artists and retailers! </p>
<p>Riia Ross art is in the very early stages but I’d love to exhibit some large original pieces and work with interior stylists in the future!

<strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>

<p>I’ve met loads of talented and likeminded people so it’s been fantastic to exchange ideas and advice within a creative network! I’ve also found the sessions with my mentor absolutely invaluable! The knowledge and experience that Chloe from ‘Cotton Clara’ has shared with me continues to be of so much value to my business and I feel really lucky to have had that opportunity! </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_4aaab9418a3d4a2b9844a9cc708e98ed~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
<strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong>

I’m very inspired by strong or flamboyant female characters - This month in particular has to be Winifred Sanders from Hocus Pocus! </p>

<p>Fleetwood Mac’s song Rhiannon is inspiring me a lot lately so I’m thinking of some lyrical artwork! </p>

<p>I’m readying ‘Conversations with Friends’ by Sally Rooney right now and there are a lot of quotes in there that have spoken to me. I’ve been dabbling with hand lettering so I have a few ideas bouncing around in my head!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_09986c8bfa974d46b3fb858f94b98cee~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>See more of what Maria does here - </strong>

<strong>Website: </strong><a href="Etsy.com/shop/URGHH" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Etsy.com/shop/URGHH</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="Etsy.com/shop/RiiaRoss" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>Etsy.com/shop/RiiaRoss</strong></u></a><strong>
</strong></p>
<p><strong>Instagram:</strong><a href=" Instagram.com/urghhdesigns" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u> Instagram.com/urghhdesigns</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="Instagram.com/riiaross " target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u><strong>Instagram.com/riiaross </strong></u></a><strong> </strong></p>

<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="Facebook.com/urghhdesigns" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Facebook.com/urghhdesigns</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Twitter: </strong><a href="Twitter.com/urghhdesigns" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>Twitter.com/urghhdesigns</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p><hr><h2>Joss McAuley</h2><p>Joss McAuley Forest School</p>

<p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>

<p>Forest School is an approach to connecting with nature that's based on the fantastic practice found in outdoor kindergartens in Denmark. It aims to give people time, space, and the skills that they need to be able to connect with natural environments in a really deep way. I did my Forest School training about 12 years ago, while I was an early years teacher, and have used it in my work ever since. I was made redundant 18 months ago, and decided to take the opportunity to go freelance. My work is pretty varied, and involves delivering sessions in early years settings and schools, working with Looked After children, families with a member with ASD, creative practitioners, and people looking to improve their mental wellbeing. I have a creative approach to my work, and incorporate elements from storytelling, music, photography, art, design and craft, to give people a unique outdoor experience and foster their creativity and imagination.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_ed3f4cbc4873405bb2087b41c0c98609~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>

<p>The freelance side of things is pretty much (variably!) my main source of income at the moment. I still keep on a little regular work on a creative project based at De Montfort University, but am hoping I'll be able to completely rely on freelance stuff by the summer (Covid allowing of course). I've already found that trying to keep up with developing my practice, learn new skills and try out new ideas, while delivering most days, is a really tricky balance!</p>

<p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>

<p>Covid has definitely been the biggest challenge so far. Having gone freelance in September 2019, I was just beginning to get established and feel more confident when Covid hit, lockdown came in, and everything stopped. I lost all of my work pretty much overnight, and had five months where I wasn't able to deliver anything, and wasn't eligible for any grants as I was newly self employed. It was great to have time to slow down, and I spent a lot of time creating resources and developing skills, but I also needed to pay the bills! Eventually I was able to offer one to one sessions in people's gardens which was a lovely, intimate way to work, and since September more opportunities for regular work have been coming in.
</p>
<p>The thing I feel proudest of up to this point is getting funding to run a wellbeing group for women who had experienced domestic abuse. Me and my Forest School buddy ran the group for six weeks just before Christmas, and despite the cold, rain and mud, the feedback we got from the ladies was great. I am really passionate about the effect that nature can have on our mental health, and to feel that I had played even a tiny part in helping someone feel better about themselves, and help them begin to develop a relationship with nature that will hopefully carry on after the group has finished and continue to be a comfort to them, that's pretty special.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7504064c15164528987d1a6afae3f4fc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>

<p>Short term, I have applied for more funding to run a longer programme of the group we ran just before Christmas, so I am crossing my fingers for that.I'm planning on putting on more Creatives Playtime sessions as soon as we are allowed. This is a session for creative and therapeutic practitioners to come together in a secret location, to relax, get inspired, and make connections with nature and each other. I also started playing with rock wrapping over the Christmas break (have a look on Youtube, it's so lovely!), so I'm practising that and playing with the techniques I'm learning. </p>

<p>Longer term, this year I am planning to establish a CIC (Community Interest Company) with a friend so that we can put more funding into delivering the creativity and mental health aspects, without having to charge people who would otherwise not be able to access this kind of thing. We are also planning that the CIC will work collaboratively with other creative practitioners and artists to deliver specific one off and longer projects, so get in touch if you are interested in working together!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_6523fefd7f3f4edc89d1e3045d488cce~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>

<p>I feel really inspired by the wonderful artists and creative community, and feel proud and privileged to be part of it. I have had two sessions with my mentor so far, and both times I have come away feeling inspired and invigorated. I constantly have nagging imposter syndrome, that I am less of a "creative" than other people, and my mentor has been so accepting of me and my practice that it has made me feel that I do have a right to call myself a creative practitioner. She also has lots of fantastic ideas that have helped me explore new possibilities and think about different ways of working.
</p>
<p><strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong></p>

<p>I am currently more than a little obsessed with a song called Funeral Singers by Sylvan Esso. I love the simplicity, melodies and rhythm, perfectly soothing and melancholy.</p>

<p>On two of the sites I am currently working at, there are Robins. They are so inquisitive and brave, so small and yet assertive and beautiful, that inspires me.</p>

<p>I am constantly inspired by family, who support and believe in me, encourage me to keep going and keep trying new things, and humour me when I get very excited about a tree, fungus, or jumping in puddles!</p>

<p><strong>You can see more of what Joss does here - </strong></p>

<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="http://instagram.com/jossmcauleyforestschool" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>instagram.com/jossmcauleyforestschool</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/jossmcauleyforestschool" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u>https://www.facebook.com/jossmcauleyforestschool</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<hr><h2>Jessica Daisy Mannings</h2><p>Jessica Mannings Art</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1289afc02d2040b494cb4fd4ab660777~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_739,h_977,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Tell us a little about your creative business and how you got into it.</strong></p>

<p>After graduating from Loughborough University with a BA (Hons) Fine Art (1st), I stayed in Loughborough, where I started my artistic career with a number of commissions, including a large mural project in town, alongside employment both full-time and part-time. When the pandemic struck, I took the situation as an opportunity to completely commit to my artistic goals, starting by creating my website, and launching my own Digital Portraits enterprise. </p>

<p><strong>How does your practice and business fit in with other life responsibilities?</strong></p>

<p>Given the current global situation, I am lucky enough to live in a house which I am renovating in exchange for rent, and so my days revolve around fixing up the property, and spending the remaining time developing my practice and business. This involves working on my website, running weekly competitions on my social media, creating art and content, and exploring all I can to fully expand myself as an individual and artist before life goes back to normal.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_1d9b442c3e5746b388f263acedab6ab8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has been your main challenge and biggest success up to this point?</strong></p>

<p>The biggest challenge I face is mental health, most prominently my eating disorder. This was severely exacerbated over quarantine, but led to a relocation and a total redirection in my life. Advocating for mental health is something I intend to direct the energies of my work towards, using my own experiences and failures to help others with similar struggles. In this way, I am determined to transform my greatest challenge into a wonderful outcome.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_713d1092fda74ca49a7af69bb2b07375~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What do you have planned for your business in the short and long term?</strong></p>

<p>In the short term, I am concentrating on Digital Portraits, whereby I am commissioned to transform photographs of individuals into unique digital paintings. This includes commemorating special events and dates, the next upcoming one being for Valentine’s Day. Long term, I will commit more focus into painting, and also in bringing together a positive, creative and healing community of like-minded individuals.</p>

<p><strong>How is the WebinArt Programme is benefitting your business journey so far?</strong></p>

<p>The mentor programme run by Webinart has been extremely helpful and insightful in giving me direction in my artistic career, and I am very grateful to John Holmes for all his advice and wise counsel. It is also very refreshing to be a part of a creative community, and to be able to bounce ideas off people and be helped by others experiences.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_664251a3ce794f74a0ff33f5090aa005~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What has inspired you recently? </strong></p>

<p>My path has been crossed with that of Ethan Sisser, a Yoga teacher, healer, coach, writer, and artist, who is affected by Glioblastoma. His strength and bravery in the face of his condition, and his spiritual message to the world has moved me deeply. Ultimately, courage in the face of adversity, and a calling for community motivates me, and alongside this, some LoFi Beats and funky fresh tunes to keep me in groove while I create.</p>

<p><strong>See more of Jessica's work here - </strong></p>
<p>
<strong>Website: </strong><a href="http://www.jessicamanningsart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>www.jessicamanningsart.com</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Instagram: </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/jessicamanningsart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>https://www.instagram.com/jessicamanningsart/</strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Facebook: </strong><a href="http://www.facebook.com/jessicamanningsart" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>www.facebook.com/jessicamanningsart</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Twitter: </strong><a href="http://twitter.com/jessicamannings" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>twitter.com/jessicamannings</strong></a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Surefire Ways to Become Your Own Creative Copywriter and Tell an Authentic Brand Story]]></title><description><![CDATA[Guest post written by Martha Moger Martha Moger is a freelance copywriter who loves creative business. She helps makers and independent...]]></description><link>https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/post/surefire-ways-to-become-your-own-creative-copywriter-and-tell-an-authentic-brand-story</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff83ec10690f30017aa71a8</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 11:30:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7eaf74fe7d374cdd8199990e4251b919~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Woody Kitson</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guest post written by Martha Moger</p>

<p><strong>Martha Moger is a freelance copywriter who loves creative business. She helps makers and independent brands to flourish by finding the words to show what they do. A valued member of the WebinArt family, Martha has been a mentor for the programme since it began in 2017.</strong></p><hr><p>It’s Spring 2017, and I’m in our spare room at home. I have two golden hours while my kids go to Grandma’s house and I’m completely consumed by an idea I can’t leave alone. I HAVE TO get my own business off the ground. </p>

<p>I’ve been trying to sell some designs in an Etsy shop but honestly, it’s not what I thought and it’s not really working. I’ve got a blog which I love but I’m not sure how to use it. The podcast I’m listening to is an interview with someone who built a business out of nothing and I’m sure there’s no difference between us. How is that person being interviewed not me?</p>

<p>One thing’s for sure - I’m not giving up. Until I find my way to be creative, get paid and do something that people need and love, I am NOT giving up. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_7eaf74fe7d374cdd8199990e4251b919~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>This moment in my history came a short while before I pitched a craft project to a massive blog in the US that I’d been a fan of for years. If you’d asked me the ultimate place for my work to appear on the internet, this would’ve been it. </p>

<p>I had nothing to lose so I went all in and sent them a project in glorious, technicolour detail. To my shock, not only did they love it, they offered to pay me for it and commissioned me to write some more. </p>

<p><strong>And that’s how I became a creative copywriter. I’m someone who uniquely understands the challenges and failures that creative people face because I’ve faced years of them too. </strong></p>

<p>So let me ask you a question. Is starting with that story a more compelling way to tell you about what I do than saying “I write words for people online”? </p>

<p>I hope it is. I hope it demonstrates how using the right words can help you to connect with others because when people connect with you, they invest. They do things like follow you around the internet (in a good way), tell their friends and buy things from you. </p>

<p>That’s why you need to become your very own creative copywriter. Here are 4 ways to do it. </p>

<p><strong>1. Know where you came from.</strong></p>

<p>To get to the heart of what you stand for and tell other people about it, you need to know where you’ve come from. The key to knowing is to ask yourself some tricky questions. </p>

<p>Bernadette Jiwa will walk you through it perfectly in her ace book, <a href="https://thestoryoftelling.com/books/story-driven/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,,<u>‘Story Driven’</u></a> There are gems like “What’s the hardest thing you’ve ever done? What did it teach you about yourself” or “Which people have had the biggest impact on your life?”</p>

<p>They’re not the kind of questions that you can come up with one-word answers to off the top of your head (probably) but that’s why they’re gold. These kinds of questions are key to figuring out why you do what you do and what drives you. They help you to tell a genuine story about the future you’re trying to create. </p>

<p>Knowing the answers can shape everything from the way you sign off emails to how you spend your profits. Killer brands are made of this. </p>

<p><strong>2. Don’t edit your bad bits, embrace them. </strong></p>

<p>The most interesting things about people often turn out to be the ones they don’t tell you. They’re usually the mistakes, the failures, the moments we’d want to change. Yet when  we share our most vulnerable experiences, these are usually the ones that resonate most.</p>

<p>I’m not talking about constant oversharing but I once did some writing for a brand that was family-run and made minimal and incredibly beautiful products inspired by nature. The business owner had been forced to scale back after growing a big business and feeling that she’d lost control. </p>

<p>Instead of sharing how she’d yearned for simplicity, a narrative so many would understand, she felt shame and wanted to hide what had happened. I thought this was a wasted opportunity since the story brought such strength, grace and deeper meaning to her brand. </p>

<p>Perfection is dull. Share your down sides.</p>

<p><strong>3. Go for emotion over facts</strong></p>

<p>When you tell a story about your product, service or work, don’t launch in with the practical bits. Deep down people don’t really care whether something is green or blue but they really care about how it either solves a problem for them or fulfills an aspiration, desire or need. </p>

<p>Think big. Those things could be as simple as looking good on the school run or owning a piece of art that makes them want to show off their living room to the universe. To do this well you really need to know your customers inside out. You need to know their hopes, dreams and what’s keeping them up at night. Show how what you do relates to what they want and feel. </p>

<p><strong>4. Different moment, different story</strong></p>

<p>Our appetite for story is enormous. 190 million subscribers to Netflix says so. Stories capture our imagination and get us hooked so that we want to know what happens next. </p>

<p>There may be one overarching back story to your work, brand or business but just like the sub-plots in your favourite TV series, there are different stories to tell at different times and in different places. </p>

<p>Think about where your target audience already is. Think again about the things that they care about. Where your story crosses over with the things your customers aspire to is where the magic really happens. </p>

<p>So start today. Know where you came from, embrace your bad bits, go for emotion and weave stories your customers will care about. </p>

<p><strong>That’s how you become your very own creative copywriter. </strong></p><hr><p><strong>Find out more about Martha and what she does here -</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://www.thestitchwriter.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.thestitchwriter.com/</u></a> </p>
<p><a href="http://instagram.com/thestitchwriter" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>http://instagram.com/thestitchwriter</u></a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.co.uk/marthamoger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.pinterest.co.uk/marthamoger/</u></a> </p>

<p>On Tuesday 12th January at 6pm, Martha will be hosting an event for WebinArt - <strong>Write Creative Copy to Tell Your Story + Engage People. </strong>If you're interested in joining this live event, you are invited to join as an Evolve WebinArt member for £4 per month. <a href="https://www.creativeleics.co.uk/webinart" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Read more here</u></a>.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/cfe882_d501888272544c0684f1c05ae03600e6~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>